<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<gameList>
    <game id="797079355">
        <path>19neunzehnj.zip</path>
        <name>19 - Neunzehn (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The heir to the throne is shared by four brave people: Darius, Simon, Thales, and Sonia. The 19 gods of Olympus left behind an omnipotent stone to the great emperor Achilles, who has ordered a search to be conducted for the stone. You take the role of one of these four in an effort to find the stone on the island before the rest, waging war with opponent armies to prevent them from finding it first.
19 is somewhat unique among turn based strategy games, in that turns are taken in real time, following rules that are reminiscent of the Japanese chess-like game known as Shogi. The game takes place on an overworld map, on which players take turns moving troops. When opposing troops vi for the same location, the game switches to a zoomed-in combat screen, showing each individual member of the opposing forces. While the story of the game revolves around finding a stone, there is no actual stone to discover. Your only goal is to wipe out the armies of the other three opponents.</desc>
        <rating>0.65</rating>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8939">Soft Pro International</developer>
        <publisher id="8939">Soft Pro International</publisher>
        <genre>Strategy</genre>
        <genreid>27</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>19neunzehn.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/19neunzehn.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/19neunzehn.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1645187739">
        <path>19neunzehn.zip</path>
        <name>19 - Neunzehn (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>The heir to the throne is shared by four brave people: Darius, Simon, Thales, and Sonia. The 19 gods of Olympus left behind an omnipotent stone to the great emperor Achilles, who has ordered a search to be conducted for the stone. You take the role of one of these four in an effort to find the stone on the island before the rest, waging war with opponent armies to prevent them from finding it first.
19 is somewhat unique among turn based strategy games, in that turns are taken in real time, following rules that are reminiscent of the Japanese chess-like game known as Shogi. The game takes place on an overworld map, on which players take turns moving troops. When opposing troops vi for the same location, the game switches to a zoomed-in combat screen, showing each individual member of the opposing forces. While the story of the game revolves around finding a stone, there is no actual stone to discover. Your only goal is to wipe out the armies of the other three opponents.</desc>
        <rating>0.65</rating>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8939">Soft Pro International</developer>
        <publisher id="8939">Soft Pro International</publisher>
        <genre>Strategy</genre>
        <genreid>27</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/19neunzehn.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/19neunzehn.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="620824853">
        <path>adiannotsue.zip</path>
        <name>Adian no Tsue (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Adian no Tsue ("Staff of Adian") is an educational action-adventure game in which you control a boy named Lucian who sets out to rescue Princess Patricia from a demon King. You must navigate levels by defeating enemies with your staff as well as solving arithmetic problems in order to earn bells and experience. Bells are the currency you'll use to buy items from the shopkeeper and 600 experience points are required in order to open the door to the next level or trigger the boss battle in specific rooms you'll need to discover.</desc>
        <rating>0.55</rating>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="37">Sunsoft</developer>
        <publisher id="37">Sunsoft</publisher>
        <genre>Educational</genre>
        <genreid>30</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/adiannotsue.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/adiannotsue.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1347413212">
        <path>aisenshinicol.zip</path>
        <name>Ai Senshi Nicol (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Help the brave inventor Nicol rescue his kidnapped girlfriend Stella from a Demon Bull King from the planet Dairass in this overhead action game. Control Nicol through 7 continents as he recovers 3 pieces on each level to his dimensional transporter invention that the Demon King stole and encased in diamonds. You'll blast away at various minions and avoid treacherous terrain while exploring multiple floors of each continent searching out the diamonds to be re-united with Stella and defeat the evil Demon King!</desc>
        <rating>1.00</rating>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Action / Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>3566</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/aisenshinicol.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/aisenshinicol.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2496739897">
        <path>akitsunofusnoka.zip</path>
        <name>Aki to Tsukasa no Fushigi no Kabe (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="3074925073">
        <path>akumajoudraculaj.zip</path>
        <name>Akumajou Dracula (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Transylvania enjoyed a century of peace thanks to the legendary hero, Christopher Belmont, a vampire hunter who vanquished Count Dracula one hundred years earlier with a holy whip named Vampire Killer. While the Easter celebration carried on with a grand carnival, evil men gathered in a monastery at the edge of the village and conducted a black mass to resurrect Count Dracula.

The men succeeded in bringing their master back. A bolt of lightning enveloped the monastery where they held the rite, signaling the resurrection of Count Dracula. When the Count returned, his Castle, which had fallen one hundred years prior, reappeared in Transylvania, and his legions of loyal minions reformed.

Simon Belmont, the descendant of Christopher Belmont, knew that as a member of the Belmont Clan and the current wielder of the Vampire Killer whip, it was his duty to bring peace and stability back to Transylvania by destroying Dracula.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>akumajoudracula.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/akumajoudracula.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/akumajoudracula.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="606451615">
        <path>akumajoudracula.zip</path>
        <name>Akumajou Dracula (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>Transylvania enjoyed a century of peace thanks to the legendary hero, Christopher Belmont, a vampire hunter who vanquished Count Dracula one hundred years earlier with a holy whip named Vampire Killer. While the Easter celebration carried on with a grand carnival, evil men gathered in a monastery at the edge of the village and conducted a black mass to resurrect Count Dracula.

The men succeeded in bringing their master back. A bolt of lightning enveloped the monastery where they held the rite, signaling the resurrection of Count Dracula. When the Count returned, his Castle, which had fallen one hundred years prior, reappeared in Transylvania, and his legions of loyal minions reformed.

Simon Belmont, the descendant of Christopher Belmont, knew that as a member of the Belmont Clan and the current wielder of the Vampire Killer whip, it was his duty to bring peace and stability back to Transylvania by destroying Dracula.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/akumajoudracula.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/akumajoudracula.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2903453025">
        <path>akuusenrai.zip</path>
        <name>Akuu Senki Raijin (Japan)</name>
        <desc>In the year 2734, the mechanical life form Garemu suddenly attacked five hyperspace navigation broadcasting points, "FIELD". In order to prevent Garem's invasion, the Milky Way alliance has decided to dispatch the mobile weapon Raijin, which you must pilot. Like Square's earlier semi-classic Thexder, the player can opt to change between the two modes of their craft at certain points during each level. Upon touching ground as the mecha, the player is occasionally able to find other directions to continue exploring as a spaceship, presenting both vertical-scrolling and side-scrolling shoot-'em-up sections. There are three items you must find before you complete a level; a star, an orb, a computer, and a bomb. After you collect all of these, it will trigger the boss battle the next time you try to go to the boss area.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="28190">Microcabin</developer>
        <publisher id="20237">Disk Original Group (DOG)</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
        <genreid>79</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/akuusenrai.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/akuusenrai.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="948183843">
        <path>aliensfix.zip</path>
        <name>Aliens - Alien 2 (Fix Hack)</name>
        <desc>Based on the Aliens movie, this unfinished prototype by Square was going to be a port of the the MSX game that was released. You'll control Ripley as she navigates side scrolling maze-like levels fighting off the alien hordes. Along the way you can collect various weapons to help make your life easier as well as a power up that allows Ripley to somersault help with the games clunky jumping controls.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8325">Square</developer>
        <publisher id="8325">Square</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/aliensfix.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/aliensfix.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1451680539">
        <path>aliens.zip</path>
        <name>Aliens - Alien 2 (Japan) (Prototype)</name>
        <desc>Based on the Aliens movie, this unfinished prototype by Square was going to be a port of the the MSX game that was released. You'll control Ripley as she navigates side scrolling maze-like levels fighting off the alien hordes. Along the way you can collect various weapons to help make your life easier as well as a power up that allows Ripley to somersault help with the games clunky jumping controls.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8325">Square</developer>
        <publisher id="8325">Square</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>aliensfix.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/aliensfix.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/aliensfix.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2597235580">
        <path>allnignipsupmabr.zip</path>
        <name>All Night Nippon Super Mario Brothers (Japan)</name>
        <desc>All Night Nippon - Super Mario Bros. was a promotional item given out as a contest prize by the Japanese radio show "All Night Nippon" to celebrate its twentieth year on the air. It combines levels from both Super Mario Bros 1 &amp; 2 and also changes graphics of items and their placements as well as graphics of enemies and mushroom retainers to members of the show.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="8934">Fuji Television Network</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/allnignipsupmabr.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/allnignipsupmabr.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3386024577">
        <path>appletowmon.zip</path>
        <name>Apple Town Monogatari - Little Computer People (Japan)</name>
        <desc>A version of Little Computer People for Nintendo's Family Computer Disk System version, published in Japan by DOG (a subsidiary of Square). Based on the original game by Activision.

Unlike previous versions of Little Computer People, the playable character is a girl wearing a pink dress and bow in her hair. The rooms of the house are also in a different configuration, featuring an outdoor balcony on the top floor. When the game is first played, a name for the character is chosen at random from a preprogrammed list. There are no winning conditions on this game you basically watch and interact with the girl in various ways. However, Apple Town Story lacks many of the features found in other versions of Little Computer People.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8325">Square</developer>
        <publisher id="20237">Disk Original Group (DOG)</publisher>
        <genre>Simulation</genre>
        <genreid>40</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/appletowmon.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/appletowmon.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3460281493">
        <path>armananokisekij.zip</path>
        <name>Armana no Kiseki (Japan)</name>
        <desc>A magic red jewel known as the Almana is stolen from an unnamed village. A thief runs off with the jewel and turns the entire village into stone. The player takes the role of Kaito a hero who resembles Indiana Jones and must travel through six cavernous levels in search of the lost jewel. Kaito's main source of transportation is unique. Besides just walking and jumping, like most platform games, he must also use a special grappling hook to reach platforms that are too high. To make things a little more difficult, the grappling hook can only be launched from a diagonal direction and not just straight above.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>armananokiseki.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/armananokiseki.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/armananokiseki.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2363531364">
        <path>armananokiseki.zip</path>
        <name>Armana no Kiseki (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>A magic red jewel known as the Almana is stolen from an unnamed village. A thief runs off with the jewel and turns the entire village into stone. The player takes the role of Kaito a hero who resembles Indiana Jones and must travel through six cavernous levels in search of the lost jewel. Kaito's main source of transportation is unique. Besides just walking and jumping, like most platform games, he must also use a special grappling hook to reach platforms that are too high. To make things a little more difficult, the grappling hook can only be launched from a diagonal direction and not just straight above.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/armananokiseki.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/armananokiseki.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3033645630">
        <path>bakutpatkun.zip</path>
        <name>Bakutoushi Patton-kun (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Bakutoushi Patton-Kun is an overhead tank combat game similar in style to Atari's Combat game. It was the first FDS title to allow for four players to play simultaneously. In the game, players attempt to destroy each others tanks. If a tank is destroyed, the driver of the tank will exit the vehicle, and must try to stay alive long enough for a replacement tank to parachute down from the sky. Game play continues until only one tank is the sole survivor. Then players advance to a new stage with different terrain. There are 56 stages in total. Tank stats can also be changed in an Editor mode. Despite referencing the name of American General George S. Patton in the title, there is no mention of him anywhere else throughout the game. Although the game was only release in Japan, the loading screen instructions contain English profanity.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8939">Soft Pro International</developer>
        <publisher id="8939">Soft Pro International</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1-4</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/bakutpatkun.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/bakutpatkun.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2360109138">
        <path>bigchadogspi.zip</path>
        <name>Big Challenge! Dogfight Spirit (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Big Challenge! Dogfight Spirit is a vertical scrolling shoot 'em up in which the player controls a blue helicopter fighting against waves of enemy vehicles and ground turrets. Each mission takes the helicopter to a different part of the world, each with a distinctive if chromatically plain visual style.

The game's power-ups, available by destroying smaller supply trucks driving across the screen, change the helicopter's weapons but do not make them stronger. It's even possible to collect the weaker original weapon again if the player is too careless. These range from a stronger forward-firing cannon (or laser) to guns that spread fire forwards and to the sides of the helicopter.

You can beat it more than once with enemies taking more hits on subsequent playthroughs.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="293">Jaleco</developer>
        <publisher id="293">Jaleco</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
        <genreid>79</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/bigchadogspi.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/bigchadogspi.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1867330129">
        <path>bigchagogobo.zip</path>
        <name>Big Challenge! Go! Go! Bowling (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Big Challenge! Go! Go! Bowling is the fourth and final game in the diverse Big Challenge series of Jaleco Famicom Disk System games, and the very last FDS game from Jaleco themselves. Go! Go! Bowling is a straightforward simulation of ten-pin bowling, the goal of which is to knock down as many pins in as few throws as possible. There are cameos of parodies of famous people including Michael Jackson that you'll bowl against in the main game mode.</desc>
        <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="293">Jaleco</developer>
        <publisher id="293">Jaleco</publisher>
        <genre>Sports</genre>
        <genreid>685</genreid>
        <players>1-4</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/bigchagogobo.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/bigchagogobo.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3317258751">
        <path>bigchagunfig.zip</path>
        <name>Big Challenge! Gun Fighter (Japan)</name>
        <desc>A sheriff must take down the outlaws of the wild west, and uncover the greater mysterious that has terrorized the town for decades. You'll scroll across stages and must defeat a certain amount of outlaws to draw out their leader and finish him off in a 3rd person shootout. Ammo is very valuable and limited in this game and must be used wisely.</desc>
        <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="293">Jaleco</developer>
        <publisher id="293">Jaleco</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/bigchagunfig.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/bigchagunfig.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2706891670">
        <path>bigchajuusen.zip</path>
        <name>Big Challenge! Juudou Senshuken (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Big Challenge! Judo Senshuken (lit. Big Challenge! Judo Championship) is a Judo-themed competitive sports game developed for the Famicom Disk System and published by Jaleco Entertainment in 1988. It is the first title in Jaleco's "Big Challenge!" series. The object of the game is to defeat the opponent using legal Judo moves. This involves a lot of grapples, pins and throws. Defeating one opponent allows the player to work their way up the tournament ranks to progressively tougher foes.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="293">Jaleco</developer>
        <publisher id="293">Jaleco</publisher>
        <genre>Fight</genre>
        <genreid>14</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/bigchajuusen.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/bigchajuusen.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2912800124">
        <path>biomirbokupa.zip</path>
        <name>Bio Miracle Bokutte Upa (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Upa is the prince of a magical kingdom and the most recent in a line of brave fighters. One day, though, he broke an urn containing the spirit of Zai, an incredibly evil goatish demon who takes the life force of the kingdom's adults and kidnaps all the babies - except for Upa, who is given a magical rattle by a fairy who was trapped in the urn along with Zai. And so, in order to save his kingdom, Upa crawls into action... He will navigating side scrolling stages with platforms and can inflate enemies by hitting them with his rattle for use as temporary platforms or to throw at adversaries.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/biomirbokupa.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/biomirbokupa.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3722633916">
        <path>bomberman.zip</path>
        <name>Bomber Man (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Our hero, Bomberman, worked in a bomb factory located in an underground labyrinth. He grew very bored making bombs day in and day out. One day, he learned of a rumor that stated if a robot could ever escape the labyrinth and reach the surface of the world, his wish would be granted and he would become human. Bomberman is determined to find out if this rumor is true.</desc>
        <releasedate>19850101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="83">Hudson</developer>
        <publisher id="83">Hudson</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/bomberman.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/bomberman.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1358980879">
        <path>bubblebobble.zip</path>
        <name>Bubble Bobble (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The game stars the twin Bubble Dragons Bub and Bob in an action-platform game in which players travel through one hundred different stages, busting and pushing bubbles, avoiding enemies and collecting a variety of items. The main goal of the game is to rescue Bub and Bob's girlfriends from monsters. In the game, each player controls one of the two Bubble Dragons, Bub and Bob. The player can move along platforms, as well as jump to those above and to the side, similar to most platform games. The dragons can blow bubbles. These can trap enemies, who are defeated if the bubble is then burst by the player's spiny back. The bubbles also float for a time before bursting, and can be jumped on, allowing access to otherwise inaccessible areas. Players progress to the next level once all enemies on the current level are defeated.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="55">Taito</developer>
        <publisher id="55">Taito</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/bubblebobble.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/bubblebobble.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2349901977">
        <path>burgertime.zip</path>
        <name>BurgerTime (Japan)</name>
        <desc>You play as Chef Pepper and your goal is to make giant hamburgers while evil eggs, sausages and pickles chase you around the game area. 

To properly make a hamburger you must assemble all of the ingredients together, dropping them from higher up onto the the burger area below. To actually do this you have to let Chef Pepper step all over the burger ingredients. As soon as an ingredient (a piece of lettuce for instance) has been stepped on, it will fall to the next level below. Falling food will squish any enemy following you and will also"bump" any other ingredient bellow it farther down. Also, as an emergency defense against the enemy food, you can collect pepper shakers which will allow you to puff out a small pepper cloud which will momentarily stun enemies, allowing you to walk past them.</desc>
        <releasedate>19850101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="88">Data East</developer>
        <publisher id="88">Data East</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/burgertime.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/burgertime.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1997349579">
        <path>chitetaiord.zip</path>
        <name>Chitei Tairiku Ordola (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Chitei Tairiku Ordola ("Underground Continent Ordola") is a Famicom Disk System action platformer from SunSoft and the third part of their Chinou Game Series, each borrowing an existing NES game's model (in Ordola's case, Atlantis no Nazo) and adding arithmetic problems to it. In Ordola, the actual math puzzles are relegated to an ancillary mini-game found on the disk.

The goal of the game is to help a young explorer pass through the underground world of Ordola, taking out enemies along the way with his bombs. The bombs fly in a specific arc, so the player needs to be the right distance from the enemy in order to hit it. The player character can also crouch, jump, climb ladders and use other abilities common to platformers.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="37">Sunsoft</developer>
        <publisher id="37">Sunsoft</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/chitetaiord.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/chitetaiord.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="515254814">
        <path>clucluland.zip</path>
        <name>Clu Clu Land (Japan)</name>
        <desc>In Clu Clu Land, the player is an female balloonfish named Bubbles who swims around in a maze trying to uncover all the golden Ingots.

Clu Clu Land's story starts with a type of sea urchin, the Unira, stealing all of the treasures in the underwater kingdom of Clu Clu Land. Bubbles, the heroine, sets out to retrieve the treasure. The object of the game is to uncover all the gold ingots in each stage while avoiding the Unira and Black Holes. Ingots usually form a shape such as a heart or a mushroom. The only way Bubbles can turn around to change directions is by means of Turning Posts located throughout the stages. Bubbles can stun the Unira by using a Sound Wave. When they are stunned, Bubbles can push them into a wall to get rid of them and receive points. If Bubbles is hurt by the Unira, she will lose a life. A life is also lost when Bubbles falls into a Black Hole, or when time runs out. The game ends if Bubbles has lost all her lives.

In later levels, the player must pass over the ingots an odd number of times to uncover them, as they will alternate between their uncovered side and a dull side.

The Famicom Disk version is based on Vs. Clu Clu Land which was released for the coin-op Nintendo Vs. System. It contained twice as many puzzles, a new enemy (Boss Unira), different level themes, and some other adjusted game features.

This is the last licensed game that was released for the Famicom Disk System. Because of this it is arguably the rarest Famicom Disk system game and sells for a large amount of money.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/clucluland.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/clucluland.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="197384621">
        <path>coconaworld.zip</path>
        <name>Cocona World (Japan)</name>
        <desc>You control a young witch who wanders throughout various parts of the kingdom. There are many animal inhabitants to interact with, some of which are good and some of which are evil. There are also a number of activities to perform and mini-games to play. Over time, the witch will request that certain activities be performed. If they are not performed within a certain time period, the player receives a penalty. Over time, the character's mood and strength will drop. If both of these are never restored and drop to zero, the game is over. This game was only released in Japan, and has never been translated into English.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="2951">SOFEL Co., Ltd.</developer>
        <publisher id="2951">SOFEL Co., Ltd.</publisher>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>13</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/coconaworld.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/coconaworld.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3060199324">
        <path>dandyj.zip</path>
        <name>Dandy - Zeuon no Fukkatsu (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>1988-20210101T000000</releasedate>
        <cloneof>dandy.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="790748111">
        <path>dandy.zip</path>
        <name>Dandy - Zeuon no Fukkatsu (T-Eng)</name>
        <releasedate>1988-20210101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="28231415">
        <path>deadzonej.zip</path>
        <name>Dead Zone (Japan)</name>
        <desc>In the space calendar 0385, the Earth suffers from overpopulation and humans started to build space colonies. Kirk, the protagonist of Dead Zone, works for the Earth federation's space development office. He is a brilliant engineer in space physics and he is working for Sirius third planet colony. He also got engaged with his beloved girlfriend Marry, but they had to postpone their wedding. Five months later, Kirk, accompanied with his robot Carry, decides to meet Marry at last, and prepare the ceremony. But when he arrives at the space station, everything is quiet. Then a beam of light hits him. He wakes up sometimes later, inside a sort of underground graveyard, pieces of dismantled robots surrounding him.

The player proceeds through the game by choosing from a selection of text menu commands. Like any traditional digital comic/text adventure games, a large view shows the surroundings. The bottom of the screen proposes simple action commands, like see, take or push; however, the game is entirely in Japanese (although it uses katakana exclusively). One of the original features of the game is to use real sampled sound in some places, which is very unusual for the time.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="37">Sunsoft</developer>
        <publisher id="37">Sunsoft</publisher>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>13</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>deadzone.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/deadzone.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/deadzone.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1669719617">
        <path>deadzone.zip</path>
        <name>Dead Zone (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>In the space calendar 0385, the Earth suffers from overpopulation and humans started to build space colonies. Kirk, the protagonist of Dead Zone, works for the Earth federation's space development office. He is a brilliant engineer in space physics and he is working for Sirius third planet colony. He also got engaged with his beloved girlfriend Marry, but they had to postpone their wedding. Five months later, Kirk, accompanied with his robot Carry, decides to meet Marry at last, and prepare the ceremony. But when he arrives at the space station, everything is quiet. Then a beam of light hits him. He wakes up sometimes later, inside a sort of underground graveyard, pieces of dismantled robots surrounding him.

The player proceeds through the game by choosing from a selection of text menu commands. Like any traditional digital comic/text adventure games, a large view shows the surroundings. The bottom of the screen proposes simple action commands, like see, take or push; however, the game is entirely in Japanese (although it uses katakana exclusively). One of the original features of the game is to use real sampled sound in some places, which is very unusual for the time.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="37">Sunsoft</developer>
        <publisher id="37">Sunsoft</publisher>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>13</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/deadzone.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/deadzone.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1544630100">
        <path>digdug.zip</path>
        <name>Dig Dug (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Dig Dug is a 1-2 player arcade game in which you have to use your shovel to dig your way through the earth. Stopping you from doing this are two monsters, called Pooka and Fygar, who will continually chase you around. The only weapon that you carry is an air pump, which you can use to inflate the monsters to the point where they explode. (if you start to inflate them but stop doing so, the monsters will get turned back to their normal selves.) Furthermore, rocks are scattered throughout the earth, and you can use these rocks to squash them. If the monsters do not find you for several seconds, they will eventually get turned into ghosts, which are able to walk through the earth. They are invincible and cannot be killed. From time to time, vegetables will appear in the center, and you can get these for points.</desc>
        <rating>0.70</rating>
        <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="68">Namco</developer>
        <publisher id="68">Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="3" parentid="0">NES</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/digdug.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/digdug.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2468469817">
        <path>digdugii.zip</path>
        <name>Dig Dug II (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Unlike the first game, Dig Dug II takes place on an island with an overhead view. The goal is simple: to kill all the enemies on the round. There are two types of enemies; Pookas (the round red monsters with goggles) only have the power to kill a player by touching him, but Fygars (the dragons) have the power to kill a player either by touching him or horizontally breathing fire to burn him.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="68">Namco</developer>
        <publisher id="68">Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/digdugii.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/digdugii.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2995725883">
        <path>dirtypaij.zip</path>
        <name>Dirty Pair - Project Eden (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Kei and Yuri, two cute space investigators, are the heroines of this side-scrolling action game by Bandai and based on the popular animation series Dirty Pair. This was released along with the movie Project Eden though it doesn't follow the plot of the actual movie all that well. Also the game is known for it's incredible difficulty.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="11038">Daiei Seisakusho</developer>
        <publisher id="580">Bandai Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <cloneof>dirtypai.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/dirtypai.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/dirtypai.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4001492008">
        <path>dirtypai.zip</path>
        <name>Dirty Pair - Project Eden (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>Kei and Yuri, two cute space investigators, are the heroines of this side-scrolling action game by Bandai and based on the popular animation series Dirty Pair. This was released along with the movie Project Eden though it doesn't follow the plot of the actual movie all that well. Also the game is known for it's incredible difficulty.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="11038">Daiei Seisakusho</developer>
        <publisher id="580">Bandai Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/dirtypai.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/dirtypai.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1120242733">
        <path>dokidokipanic.zip</path>
        <name>Doki Doki Panic (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Yume Kōjō: Doki Doki Panic (translated as Dream Factory: Heart-Pounding Panic and usually referred to as Doki Doki Panic) is a Japan-only video game developed by Nintendo in cooperation with Fuji Television (who also made All Night Nippon Super Mario Bros.) for the Family Computer Disk System to promote its event called Yume Kōjō '87 (translates to Dream Factory '87).

It was later released outside of Japan in an altered format under the name Super Mario Bros. 2, since the original Japanese Super Mario Bros. sequel, Super Mario Bros.: The Lost Levels, was deemed too similar to the original and too difficult for overseas players. Eventually, the altered Mario version of Doki Doki Panic was released in Japan as well, under the title Super Mario USA.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="3" parentid="0">NES</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/dokidokipanic.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/dokidokipanic.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2235073932">
        <path>donkeykong.zip</path>
        <name>Donkey Kong (Japan)</name>
        <desc>You are Mario, and that big old gorilla, Donkey Kong, has run off with your girlfriend. It's up to you to struggle up those ladders and balance on those beams to rescue your lady fair. She's held captive at the very top. But Donkey Kong is not ready to give her up so easily. He's tossing barrels and fireballs at you at every turn. It's up to you to outmaneuver that wily ape. Good luck, your lady awaits!</desc>
        <releasedate>19810101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/donkeykong.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/donkeykong.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4213130367">
        <path>donkeykongjr.zip</path>
        <name>Donkey Kong Jr. (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Mario has gone mad! He's turned the tables on Donkey Kong and locked him in a cage. It's up to you, as Donkey Kong Jr., to rescue your father by stealing Mario's set of keys. But it won't be easy. You'll have to fight off ape-eating Snapjaws, jump onto moving islands and break through a jungle of vines to get to the keys that will free Donkey Kong. Can you handle the action? Because this off-the-wall monkey business will have you going bananas!</desc>
        <releasedate>19820101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/donkeykongjr.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/donkeykongjr.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4070153922">
        <path>drcha.zip</path>
        <name>Dr. Chaos - Jigoku no Tobira (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Dr. Chaos is a side-scrolling action adventure developped by Marionette and published by Pony Canyon. The genius scientist Dr Ginn Chaos has gone missing. Before his disappearance, he was actively working in his large mansion on a device allowing access to alternate dimensions. Armed only with a knife, his brother decides to look for him and ultimately unveil the mystery behind the incident. Something obviously went terribly wrong with Dr. Chaos's experiment, and the goal of the game is to locate all the eleven dimensional warp-zones hidden within the mansion, as well as assembling a powerful laser gun, the only weapon capable of taking down the last boss.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8966">Marionette Co., Ltd.</developer>
        <publisher id="2870">Pony Canyon</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/drcha.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/drcha.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4282054667">
        <path>dracuii.zip</path>
        <name>Dracula II - Noroi no Fuuin (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The game's setting takes place seven years after the original Castlevania. The prologue begins when Simon visits his family's resting ground. His back is critically injured from his last encounter with Dracula in the previous game. He suddenly feels someone's presence, and turns to see a young woman standing within the mist. She tells him that a curse was placed upon him by Dracula during their last battle, and that he does not have long to live. The woman continues to say that the curse can be undone if he resurrects Dracula himself. She further explains that Dracula's body was split into five different parts after his defeat seven years ago, and Simon must recover these and bring them to the ruins of Dracula's castle. There, he must seal Dracula and defeat him. Before disappearing, the unknown woman says she cannot guarantee that this will destroy Dracula permanently.

Dracula II - Noroi no Fuuin (Lit. "Dracula II: The Seal of the Curse") is an action-adventure game produced by Konami. It was originally released for the Family Computer Disk System in Japan in 1987, and for the NES in North America in 1988. It is the second Castlevania title released for the NES, following the original Castlevania. Set in 1698, seven years after the events of the first installment, the player once again assumes the role of vampire hunter Simon Belmont, who is on a journey to undo a curse placed on him by Dracula at the end of their previous encounter. Small differences exist between the Japanese version and the American version. Specifically the Japanese version takes advantage of the expanded FM processing capabilities of the FDS hardware to produce better sound, but it contains load scenes when entering or exiting any town or mansion. The FDS version also has three save slots instead of the NES password system.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/dracuii.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/dracuii.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="873548363">
        <path>druid.zip</path>
        <name>Druid - Kyoufu no Tobira (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Druid is an action game inspired by the arcade hit Gauntlet. As the eponymous hero, your job is to destroy four magic skulls hidden over eight levels.The game is presented in a top-down view. The druid walks around the terrain seeking out the staircase that leads to the next level. On the way, he is harassed by hordes of monsters that come out of every direction and attack him, decreasing his health. To defend himself, the druid can use the spells of water, fire or electricity to toss projectiles. However, these magical weapons have limited ammo.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="293">Jaleco</developer>
        <publisher id="293">Jaleco</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/druid.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/druid.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2253351365">
        <path>eggerland.zip</path>
        <name>Egger Land (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The Eggerland series is better known outside of Japan as The Adventure of Lolo series.The game is often referred to as "Syodai", or the "first one". The game is a remake of "Meikyuu Shinwa" (Eggerland 2; lit. "Labyrinth Myth") for the MSX2 Home Computer System with updated graphics and different music. Furthermore, in this remake the location of some special rooms was swapped, and a final boss battle was introduced.In this Eggerland, Lolo must navigate his way through a non-linear series of rooms, the majority of which occupy a 10x10 arrangement along the main floor of a castle. Many rooms have more than one exit for Lolo to choose from, and a map can be collected along the way to provide the player with information about where he or she is, and what rooms have already been visited. Secret entrances to hidden chambers must be found so that keys can be collected, enabling the player to explore deeper into the castle.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="457">HAL Laboratory</developer>
        <publisher id="457">HAL Laboratory</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/eggerland.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/eggerland.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3235290386">
        <path>eggerlansouenota.zip</path>
        <name>Egger Land - Souzouhe no Tabidachi (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Souzou he no Tabidachi translates to "Departure to Creation." Like with "Revival of the Labyrinth" before, this is a fitting description of the game itself. It references the fact that it brings the Creation Mode from the original back to the series, after it was abandoned in the previous two installments. It further resembles the first title in that it's also one of the most basic entries in the franchise, and among the easiest of the Japanese releases. It's also tied for the shortest game in the entire series, with just fifty puzzles in all. Given that the predecessors all had a hundred or more, this might seems like a problem, but the caliber of the puzzles is as high as ever. So if you found the prequels to be a bit overwhelming, then this might be the best of the early titles to start with. Interestingly, this seems to have been one of the FDS titles that were available solely from Disk Writer machines, as it doesn't appear to have ever been released at retail.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="457">HAL Laboratory</developer>
        <publisher id="457">HAL Laboratory</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/eggerlansouenota.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/eggerlansouenota.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3431120054">
        <path>electrician1.zip</path>
        <name>Electrician (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The player character is a young electrician called Richard Light. He must install electrical wiring in apartment buildings in various American cities. In each building, Richard navigates service corridors to link the electrical wires between each room, As he does so, animals threaten to chew through the wires. When an electrical connection is complete, the live wires illuminate the connected rooms and electrocute the "enemy" animals on contact. If Richard touches any of the rats, bats, or giant insects in the corridor, he loses a life. In the buildings, the player earns points by illuminating rooms and electrocuting any rats, bats, and insects. Occasionally, a burglar appears; intercepting him rewards the player with bonus points and a bell, which is worth a 1-up.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="4635">Synapse Software Corporation</developer>
        <publisher id="462">Kemco</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>electrician.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/electrician.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/electrician.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1803836742">
        <path>electrician.zip</path>
        <name>Electrician (T-eng)</name>
        <desc>The player character is a young electrician called Richard Light. He must install electrical wiring in apartment buildings in various American cities. In each building, Richard navigates service corridors to link the electrical wires between each room, As he does so, animals threaten to chew through the wires. When an electrical connection is complete, the live wires illuminate the connected rooms and electrocute the "enemy" animals on contact. If Richard touches any of the rats, bats, or giant insects in the corridor, he loses a life. In the buildings, the player earns points by illuminating rooms and electrocuting any rats, bats, and insects. Occasionally, a burglar appears; intercepting him rewards the player with bonus points and a bell, which is worth a 1-up.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="4635">Synapse Software Corporation</developer>
        <publisher id="462">Kemco</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/electrician.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/electrician.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4046765775">
        <path>esperdreamj.zip</path>
        <name>Esper Dream (Japan)</name>
        <desc>This is a story that occurred in the distant village from where you live.
This village was filled with a beautiful, quiet, and mysterious aroma.

However, the villagers suffered from an unexpected tragedy.
The Evil clan called Narcisse tribe, began searching for the magic hidden in our village.

Even worse, they kidnapped the daughter of our mayor, Alice.

Please, go forth and rescue Alice, and bring peace to our land!</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Role playing games</genre>
        <genreid>8</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>esperdream.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/esperdream.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/esperdream.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1598996567">
        <path>esperdream.zip</path>
        <name>Esper Dream (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>This is a story that occurred in the distant village from where you live.
This village was filled with a beautiful, quiet, and mysterious aroma.

However, the villagers suffered from an unexpected tragedy.
The Evil clan called Narcisse tribe, began searching for the magic hidden in our village.

Even worse, they kidnapped the daughter of our mayor, Alice.

Please, go forth and rescue Alice, and bring peace to our land!</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Role playing games</genre>
        <genreid>8</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/esperdream.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/esperdream.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3107616324">
        <path>excitsoc.zip</path>
        <name>Exciting Soccer - Konami Cup (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Players select one of the various soccer teams, and aim to become the best team in the league. Each team possesses different levels of kick strength, endurance, dribbling technique, defensive skill, and luck. They are set at the beginning of the game, but can be enhanced through training. During play, the view of the field is a bird's eye view, with either goal located at the far top and bottom sections of the field. Although this game is considered a relatively minor release, it's ending BGM entitled "Seaside Memory" is highly revered.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Sports / Soccer</genre>
        <genreid>2847</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/excitsoc.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/excitsoc.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3053621942">
        <path>fairypin.zip</path>
        <name>Fairy Pinball - Yousei Tachi no Pinball (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="2781495280">
        <path>falsion.zip</path>
        <name>Falsion (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Humanity has colonized most planets in our galaxy, the Milky Way, and they now look towards expanding their reach by using an experimental travel technology called "Hyperzone Drive". However, a race of aliens who have already mastered that technology are currently invading planets at a quick pace, closing in on our solar system. The invaders attack humanity's colony on Pluto and conquer it with little resistance, since human civilization doesn't have the technology to defend itself.

The human organization responsible for the space program, the "United Space Force", decides to use the yet-untested "Hyperzone Drive" in order to send ships that will directly attack the armies of the invading aliens. However, the new technology proves hard to control, and only one of the ships manages to survive the trip: Falsion.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Shooter</genre>
        <genreid>2646</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/falsion.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/falsion.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2902481140">
        <path>famicgrapri.zip</path>
        <name>Famicom Grand Prix - F1 Race (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Compete in championships or try to beat your best time in this top-down Formula 1 racing game.

Famicom Grand Prix: F1 Race gives you 10 tracks to race on with either dry or rainy conditions. On top of keeping all four wheels on the road, tire wear, damage, and fuel must be managed to secure victory. Stopping into the pit for maintenance at the right moment can mean the difference between victory and defeat. There are also 24 different cars to purchase with your winnings with varying attributes including speed, fuel efficiency, body strength, and tire endurance.

F1 Race was released as one of Nintendo's Disk Fax line of games. It came on a special blue disk and allowed players to submit their best times through special kiosks in various stores across Japan. Players with the best time were given a chance to win a Super Mario Bros. Game &amp; Watch LCD game.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Race, Driving</genre>
        <genreid>28</genreid>
        <players>1-4</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/famicgrapri.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/famicgrapri.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="184731053">
        <path>famicgrapriii.zip</path>
        <name>Famicom Grand Prix II - 3D Hot Rally (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="1208682186">
        <path>famimdisvol1.zip</path>
        <name>Famimaga Disk Vol. 1 - Hong Kong (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Hong Kong, or Famimaga Disk Vol. 1 Hong Kong, is a Shanghai variant in which players must remove specified tiles from a pattern. The player can select which pattern (from pyramids and hourglasses to more complex designs) from which to draw tiles as well as inputting a three letter code which offers several thousand possible combinations of the tiles within that pattern.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8763">Tokuma Shoten</developer>
        <publisher id="8763">Tokuma Shoten</publisher>
        <genre>Strategy</genre>
        <genreid>27</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/famimdisvol1.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/famimdisvol1.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="510008251">
        <path>famimdisvol2.zip</path>
        <name>Famimaga Disk Vol. 2 - Panic Space (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Panic Space, or Famimaga Disk Vol. 2 Panic Space, is a puzzle game in which the goal is to reflect a laser to an exit panel in order to open the way to the next stage. The laser cannot hit any of the stage's surrounding wall: were it do so, it would cause the level to explode and the player to lose a life (from an initial allotment of five, though this can be increased while playing the game). Much of the time the various reflectors (which send the beam off at a 90 degree angle) and blocks (which simply stop the laser in its tracks) must be maneuvered into place before the laser should be tested on them.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8763">Tokuma Shoten</developer>
        <publisher id="8763">Tokuma Shoten</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/famimdisvol2.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/famimdisvol2.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="840309495">
        <path>famimdisvol3.zip</path>
        <name>Famimaga Disk Vol. 3 - All 1 (Japan)</name>
        <desc>All One, or Famimaga Disk Vol. 3 All One, is a puzzle game in which the player controls a ladybug pushing over dice. The goal of each stage is to push all the dice onto their side so that their "one" side is facing upwards. The player is given a smaller first-person view window from the ladybug's perspective to allow them to see the sides of each die and plan out their strategy.</desc>
        <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8763">Tokuma Shoten</developer>
        <publisher id="8763">Tokuma Shoten</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/famimdisvol3.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/famimdisvol3.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1158381548">
        <path>famimdisvol4.zip</path>
        <name>Famimaga Disk Vol. 4 - Clox (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Clox, or Famimaga Disk Vol. 4 Clox, is a falling blocks puzzle game that is superficially similar to Tetris or Columns. Single clock faces depicting one of four angles fall from the top and the player needs to manipulate and place them so they can form larger objects, such as simple formations like squares, diamonds and hourglass shapes to more object-intensive shapes like octagons and hexagons.</desc>
        <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8763">Tokuma Shoten</developer>
        <publisher id="8763">Tokuma Shoten</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/famimdisvol4.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/famimdisvol4.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3943317212">
        <path>famimdisvol5.zip</path>
        <name>Famimaga Disk Vol. 5 - Puyo Puyo (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Puyo Puyo is the first entry of Compile's Puyo Puyo series. It was released on the MSX and Famicom Disk System on October 25, 1991; the FDS version was published by Tokuma Shoten as part of their "Famimaga Disk" line of games. The FDS version would later be released on a Famicom cart in 1993. Puyo Puyo would be succeeded by a much more popular arcade game of the same name.</desc>
        <releasedate>19910101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="48">Compile</developer>
        <publisher id="8763">Tokuma Shoten</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/famimdisvol5.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/famimdisvol5.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2569961517">
        <path>famimdisvol6.zip</path>
        <name>Famimaga Disk Vol. 6 - Janken Disk Jou (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Janken Disk Jou, or Famimaga Disk Vol. 6 Janken Disk Jou, is a puzzle game in which the protagonist (who looks uncannily like Disk-kun, the mascot of the Famicom Disk System) must brave a labyrinth of puzzles. In each room there are three variants of hand-shaped blocks between the hero and the exit: each one either making the "scissors" gesture, the "rock" gesture or the "paper" gesture. Pushing a block adjacent to another of a different type causes whichever was the inferior (e.g. with paper and rock, rock is the inferior) to vanish. In addition, each block has a "strength" which is signified by its color: green is level 1, yellow is level 2 and red is level 3. If a green block is pushed next to an inferior red block, the red block will instead become yellow instead of vanishing (and then green with a subsequent superior block, and then will vanish after a third).</desc>
        <releasedate>19920101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8763">Tokuma Shoten</developer>
        <publisher id="8763">Tokuma Shoten</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/famimdisvol6.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/famimdisvol6.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3953250001">
        <path>fdsirqtest.zip</path>
        <name>FDS IRQ Test (Sour, v7)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="1028980309">
        <path>fdsbios.zip</path>
        <name>FDS System BIOS</name>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/fdsbios.png</image>
    </game>
    <game id="3440037456">
        <path>finalcom.zip</path>
        <name>Final Command - Akai Yousai (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Your brothers-in-arms are hostages behind enemy lines, and you're their only hope for freedom. But the firepower you'll face to rescue them is awesome. Cannons, tanks, submarines and snipers will blast you with horrific crossfire, while jet fighters zero in from above. To defend yourself, you control the army's advanced all-terrain attack jeep, with its arsenal of guided missiles and incendiary grenades. Of course these are merely tools, and to save your countrymen you'll need more than a handful of gunpowder. You'll need a pocketful of miracles, and the ferocity of a wild Jackal!</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
        <genreid>79</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/finalcom.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/finalcom.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2132439461">
        <path>firebam.zip</path>
        <name>Fire Bam (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Bam is a fifteen years old courageous boy. Like every boy his age, Bam must pass the village's test and bring back an insect's shell from the forest. But as he returns, and to his surprise, most of the village has been destroyed and his parents turned into demons. Armed with his sword, Bam sets forth in search of what happened to the village and his parents.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="457">HAL Laboratory</developer>
        <publisher id="457">HAL Laboratory</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/firebam.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/firebam.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2435252815">
        <path>firerock.zip</path>
        <name>Fire Rock (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Fire Rock is an action game developed for the Famicom Disk System by System Sacom, and published in Japan by Use in 1988. The design of the game is credited to Mark Flint. In the game, the player controls what appears to be a cave man, whose goal is to navigate a series of item filled caverns in an effort to locate the boss of the level, defeat it, and then locate the door which leads to the next level. The game is commonly sited as having very poor controls, often requiring the player to grab hold of a wall, and very slowly climb it by holding up and tapping jump repeatedly. Other issues include a very low jump that places more platforms and items out of reach, and a difficult time bringing the character back under control if he starts to slip. This game was not released outside of Japan.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="151">System Sacom</developer>
        <publisher id="8891">Use Corporation</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/firerock.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/firerock.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="516221152">
        <path>fuuunshoken.zip</path>
        <name>Fuuun Shourin Ken (Japan)</name>
        <desc>In Fuuun Shourin Ken, you control a rising martial artist who strives to defeat other great fighters. To do so, you must utilize a wide array of attacks to defeat your opponent before they knock you out first. You will compete in six different scenes against 13 different opponents. The game follows in the vein of Yie Ar Kung-Fu, and predates the original Street Fighter by only a couple of months. It features similar concepts such as a distinction between punch and kick attacks, relative directions, and a health bar for each fighter, depicted as a series of paper fans.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="293">Jaleco</developer>
        <publisher id="293">Jaleco</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/fuuunshoken.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/fuuunshoken.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="703866175">
        <path>galaga.zip</path>
        <name>Galaga (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The objective of Galaga is to score as many points as possible by destroying insect-like enemies. The player controls a starfighter that can move left and right along the bottom of the playfield. Enemies swarm in groups in a formation near the top of the screen, and then begin flying down toward the player, firing bullets at and attempting to crash into them. In later stages, some enemies even break from an entering group in a frantic attempt to crash into the player. The game ends when the player's last fighter is lost by colliding with an enemy, being hit by an enemy bullet, or being captured.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="68">Namco</developer>
        <publisher id="68">Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em up / Vertical</genre>
        <genreid>2851</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/galaga.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/galaga.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="424875337">
        <path>galaxian.zip</path>
        <name>Galaxian (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The gameplay is relatively simple. Swarm after swarm of alien armies attack the player's ship that moves left and right at the bottom of the wraparound screen. The ship can only have one shot on screen at a time. The player defeats one swarm, only to have it replaced by another more aggressive and challenging swarm in the next stage. A plain and repetitive starfield scrolls in the background.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="68">Namco</developer>
        <publisher id="68">Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
        <genreid>79</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/galaxian.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/galaxian.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="867431326">
        <path>gallforj.zip</path>
        <name>Gall Force - Eternal Story (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Based upon the anime of the same name, Gall Force is a group of science fiction anime OAV series by the studio Artmic, with production by Youmex and AIC. The original character designs were by Kenichi Sonoda. In the original story line, an all-out, prehistoric galactic war rages between the all-female Solnoids and the amorphous Paranoids for too long. In the midst of battle, a plan which was secretly hatched by the leaders of both sides comes into fruition, and an unsuspecting crew of seven Solnoid soldiers aboard the Kulanis-class Cruiser named the Star Leaf is caught up in the middle.

The Famicom Disk System game is a top down shooter and follows a different story than that of the OAVs. It features Rabby flying across Terra, and catapulting into six different regions of space in order to rescue each of her crew members one at a time. With each crew member that you rescue, you gain access to a new configuration for your ship.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="457">HAL Laboratory</developer>
        <publisher id="457">HAL Laboratory</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>gallfor.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/gallfor.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/gallfor.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3236185068">
        <path>gallfor.zip</path>
        <name>Gall Force - Eternal Story (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>Based upon the anime of the same name, Gall Force is a group of science fiction anime OAV series by the studio Artmic, with production by Youmex and AIC. The original character designs were by Kenichi Sonoda. In the original story line, an all-out, prehistoric galactic war rages between the all-female Solnoids and the amorphous Paranoids for too long. In the midst of battle, a plan which was secretly hatched by the leaders of both sides comes into fruition, and an unsuspecting crew of seven Solnoid soldiers aboard the Kulanis-class Cruiser named the Star Leaf is caught up in the middle.

The Famicom Disk System game is a top down shooter and follows a different story than that of the OAVs. It features Rabby flying across Terra, and catapulting into six different regions of space in order to rescue each of her crew members one at a time. With each crew member that you rescue, you gain access to a new configuration for your ship.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="457">HAL Laboratory</developer>
        <publisher id="457">HAL Laboratory</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/gallfor.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/gallfor.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2697861067">
        <path>gingaden.zip</path>
        <name>Ginga Denshou - Galaxy Odyssey (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Ginga Denshou - Galaxy Odyssey is a game developed for the Family Computer Disk System by Wave Jack, and published by Imagineer in 1986. Unlike most games for the FDS, Galaxy Odyssey did not come with just a disk and an instruction booklet. Among the contents found in the large box, were an audio cassette tape and a book recounting the game's story.The game itself is quite unusual as well. It features a blend of vertical shooting gameplay mixed with more Zelda-like exploration sequences. As the pilot of a ship, you could dock with certain dungeon entrances, and take a shuttle down to the ground to explore and search for items. Searching around isn't easy at first, since you run out of oxygen fairly quickly, and that starts to drain your life, of which you start out with three bars.To win the game, you must find the medicine needed to rescue the people who are suffering from a disease in your home area. To do so, you must collect warp codes, and translate alien codes, and blast off from one dungeon location to travel to another. The game's text is in Japanese, and has never been translated to another language.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="466">Imagineer</developer>
        <publisher id="466">Imagineer</publisher>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>13</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/gingaden.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/gingaden.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1903925247">
        <path>golf.zip</path>
        <name>Golf (Japan)</name>
        <desc>A port of the Nintendo Famicom game to the Famicom Disk System.

Golf is a sports-simulation video game released in 1984. The golfer is a mustached man who resembles Mario.

The player one character wears a white shirt and shoes with blue pants and uses a white ball, while the player two character wears a red shirt and shoes with black pants and uses a red ball.

The user must first decide whether to play single stroke play or the two player selections of doubles stroke play or match play. The user is then placed at the tee of the first hole of eighteen.</desc>
        <releasedate>19840101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Sports / Golf</genre>
        <genreid>2913</genreid>
        <players>2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/golf.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/golf.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4292723100">
        <path>golfjapcou.zip</path>
        <name>Golf - Japan Course (Japan)</name>
        <desc>An update of sorts to Golf. Players get to take control of Nintendo's mascots Mario and Luigi (in the 2 player game) and play over 18 holes of golf on courses modeled after real courses in Japan.

Players can choose to either try their skills in match play or stroke play. Match play involves two golfers trying to win the most holes. They win holes by getting the better score than their competitor. Stroke play differs as it just involves the golfer trying to get the best score possible by completing each hole in as few strokes as possible.

When on the golf course, players can choose the club they want to use, adjust the speed and strength (from a 1 to 3 scale) of their swing, and aim in the direction they want to hit the ball. Hitting the ball involves the use of a meter with an icon that goes back and forth, which gauges the distance the ball is hit. Players can take a step back from the tee and take practice swings so they can get into a rhythm using this meter.

This game also contained a now defunct feature where players could record their personal information and their best scores and then bring the game disk to a Disk Fax machine. Inserting the disk into this machine would fax over the player's information to Nintendo's headquarters. This information was used for a contest. Being selected a contest winner would award the player with a golden colored disk version of this game. This golden disk version of the game contained an exclusive course that was not present on the original version of this game.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="457">HAL Laboratory</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Sports / Golf</genre>
        <genreid>2913</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/golfjapcou.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/golfjapcou.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="500136687">
        <path>golfuscourse.zip</path>
        <name>Golf - US Course (Japan)</name>
        <desc>A slightly updated companion title to Golf - Japan Course released just a few months earlier. The graphics are more updated and the gameplay is a little more advanced as well. Players get to take control of Nintendo's mascots Mario and Luigi (in the 2 player game) and play over 18 holes of golf on courses modeled after real courses in the USA.

Players can choose to either try their skills in match play or stroke play. Match play involves two golfers trying to win the most holes. They win holes by getting the better score than their competitor. Stroke play differs as it just involves the golfer trying to get the best score possible by completing each hole in as few strokes as possible.

When on the golf course, players can choose the club they want to use, adjust the speed and strength (from a 1 to 3 scale) of their swing, and aim in the direction they want to hit the ball. Hitting the ball involves the use of a meter with an icon that goes back and forth, which gauges the distance the ball is hit. Players can take a step back from the tee and take practice swings so they can get into a rhythm using this meter.

This game also contained a now defunct feature where players could record their personal information and their best scores and then bring the game disk to a Disk Fax machine. Inserting the disk into this machine would fax over the player's information to Nintendo's headquarters. This information was used for a contest. Being selected a contest winner would award the player with a golden colored disk version of this game. This golden disk version of the game contained an exclusive course that was not present on the original version of this game.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="457">HAL Laboratory</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Sports / Golf</genre>
        <genreid>2913</genreid>
        <players>2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/golfuscourse.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/golfuscourse.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4186048564">
        <path>goonies.zip</path>
        <name>Goonies, The (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The Goonies was developed by Konami in 1986. Naturally, it is based somewhat on the movie of the same name, where a boy named Mikey and his friends discover the treasure of a pirate just in time to prevent their home town from being bought out by greedy land developers. While the game incoporates some of the more identifiable aspects of the movie, it follows a decidedly different plot line, with the gang of Mikey's friend captured by the Frateli family, one of the movie's antagonists. Mikey is therefore required to proceed from stage to stage and rescue them, while exploring labyrinthine dungeons and locating power-up items.  There are six stages in all. Power-ups and diamonds are hidden from sight. To reveal them, players must discover the particular joystick input specific to the stage they are hidden in. After the player completes the stages at the first level of difficulty, the input required for each stage changes in the second level. Many secrets are scattered throughout the game including cameos from the likes of Konamiman, and Twinbee. Even a secret warp can be found in order to bypass one level. Many of the features and items introduced in this version found their way into the more advanced sequel.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Action / Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>3566</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/goonies.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/goonies.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2350662236">
        <path>greenberet.zip</path>
        <name>Green Beret (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Based on the arcade game of the same name, the player's objective in the FDS version was changed from rescuing prisoners to destroying a secret weapon being developed in the enemy's headquarters. Additionally, a 2-players co-operative mode was introduced as well, allowing two players to play simultaneously (with Player 1 in blue and Player 2 in red). The play mechanics are essentially identical to the arcade version, however the Flamethrower is removed (only the Rocket Launcher and Grenades remained) and two new power-up items are introduced: a Star mark which grants invincibility and a pistol with unlimited ammo, both which are only usable for a limited period. The FDS version also features two additional stages that were not in the arcade game: an airport set between the Missile Base and the Harbor, where the player faces a group of rocket soldiers at the end; and a new final stage set inside the enemy's base in which the player must disarm a nuclear missile at the end that is about to be launched; by using rocket launchers dropped by enemy soldiers. The flamethrower corps at the end of the Warehouse stage was replaced by a paratrooper unit.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/greenberet.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/greenberet.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2370667478">
        <path>gunsmoke.zip</path>
        <name>Gun.Smoke (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The objective is to free the town of Hicksville from the band of criminals known as the Wingates. But in order to capture their most dangerous henchmen, in each stage the player must retrieve a Wanted sign of said henchman, otherwise it is impossible to clear the stage. In this game, the main character is a bounty hunter named Billy Bob.

Although virtually identical to the NES version, the FDS version featured several differences:

This game, like virtually all other FDS games, feature load times.

The font is similar to what is used in most Capcom games on the Famicom/NES. However, on the NES version, the font is changed to the military-font, also seen in the arcade version.

"In America" is changed to "In 1849".
Bandit Bill's mugshot on the wanted poster is slightly different in both versions of the game. In the FDS version, his shirt has an open collar, with part of his body showing. In the NES version, his shirt has a scarf around it. On top of that, the mugshots for the wanted posters originally had an Anime look, whereas in the NES version, they had a realistic look.

In this version, the shopping music features less instruments. Also, many of the tunes featured in the NES version are nowhere to be found in this version, and instead recycle the same music for certain scenes in the game. This is due to the limited memory space in FDS disk cards.

There is no game demonstration like there is in the NES version.

After beating the game the first two times, the player is rewarded with a Japanese message that tells the player to try the game again. After the third time, the player will be rewarded with a simple message that says "THE END". The Japanese message was thrown out in the NES version, instead of being translated into English.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="31">Capcom</developer>
        <publisher id="31">Capcom</publisher>
        <genre>Shooter</genre>
        <genreid>2646</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/gunsmoke.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/gunsmoke.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3455084532">
        <path>gyruss1.zip</path>
        <name>Gyruss (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The entire solar system is being attacked by the vicious Gyrusians, and it's up to you to save the day! You will need to fly your spaceship to each of the nine planets and then clear three stages of enemies to rid that planet of the Gyrusians. You start the game with a single canon, and can gain a double canon after shooting a power up satelite. After clearing each planet, there is another bonus stage where additional weapons and bonus points can be collected. Gyruss is an arcade action shooter, however instead of piloting your spaceship horizontally or vertically, you move in a circle around the perimeter of the screen. The NES version of Gyruss adds to the original arcade version additional music, additional weapons, new enemies, and a large boss at the end of each level.</desc>
        <rating>0.70</rating>
        <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="27077">Ultra Games</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
        <genreid>79</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>gyruss.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="3" parentid="0">NES</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/gyruss.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/gyruss.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1569211095">
        <path>gyruss.zip</path>
        <name>Gyruss (T-eng)</name>
        <desc>The entire solar system is being attacked by the vicious Gyrusians, and it's up to you to save the day! You will need to fly your spaceship to each of the nine planets and then clear three stages of enemies to rid that planet of the Gyrusians. You start the game with a single canon, and can gain a double canon after shooting a power up satelite. After clearing each planet, there is another bonus stage where additional weapons and bonus points can be collected. Gyruss is an arcade action shooter, however instead of piloting your spaceship horizontally or vertically, you move in a circle around the perimeter of the screen. The NES version of Gyruss adds to the original arcade version additional music, additional weapons, new enemies, and a large boss at the end of each level.</desc>
        <rating>0.70</rating>
        <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="27077">Ultra Games</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
        <genreid>79</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="3" parentid="0">NES</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/gyruss.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/gyruss.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1045840699">
        <path>halleywars.zip</path>
        <name>Halley Wars (Japan)</name>
        <desc>It’s the middle of the 21st century. The armies of Lord Halley are launching attacks on planet Earth. You are the last chance for Earth, piloting a craft specially developed to engage these hordes. You must fight your way through their defenses to the final goal, the alien base. The final battle is about to commence!

Halley Wars is a vertical scrolling shooter. The game has 6 stages set in locations in space such as, above planets or in asteroid fields. There are end of levels bosses at the end of each stage each with their own weaknesses. There are power-ups, which can be picked up along the way when you shoot particular asteroids or satellites. These upgrade your weapon strength, speed, add explosive pods and shields.

Where the game stood out was, there are comets that need to be destroyed on your journey. Each comet and ship that you don’t shoot makes it to earth and does some damage there. Comets do more damage than the enemy ships do. If Earths damage level reaches 100% the game is over. For every 2000 points you score, 1% of Earths damage is repaired.
</desc>
        <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="9612">ITL Co., Ltd.</developer>
        <publisher id="55">Taito</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em up / Vertical</genre>
        <genreid>2851</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/halleywars.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/halleywars.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="169664576">
        <path>haokunnofusnata.zip</path>
        <name>Hao-kun no Fushigi na Tabi (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="3580501960">
        <path>hikarshi.zip</path>
        <name>Hikari Shinwa - Palutena no Kagami (Japan)</name>
        <desc>In a time where humans and gods coexisted in harmony, the kingdom of Angel Land was ruled by two goddesses, Palutena the Goddess of Light and Medusa the Goddess of Darkness. While Palutena administered the light and helped the mortals cultivate their crops, Medusa despised the mortals and used the darkness to destroy their crops and turn the mortals into stone. Enraged, Palutena transformed Medusa into a hideous monster and banished her into the dark Underworld.

But Medusa would not go quietly. She assembled an army of monsters and evil spirits of the underworld to conquer Palutena's home, the Palace in the Sky. War erupted and Medusa's minions overwhelmed Palutena's army, eventually imprisoning the Goddess of Light. Medusa then seized the Three Sacred Treasuresâ€”the Mirror Shield, the Arrow of Light, and the Wings of Pegasusâ€”and gave them to her most powerful minions.

Defeated and imprisoned, Palutena's only hope was to seek the help of Pit, a young angel trapped in the Underworld. Using the last of her strength, she sent Pit a magical bow. Thus, Pit set out on a quest to escape the Underworld, retrieve the Sacred Treasures that would help him defeat Medusa, and rescue Palutena and restore peace to Angel Land.

The original Famicom Disk System versions feature save slots, unlike the North American version which uses a password system (known in-game as "Sacred Words"). As with Metroid, the FDS version of Kid Icarus also features higher-quality music and sound effects that take advantage of the system's additional sound channels.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/hikarshi.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/hikarshi.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3256339116">
        <path>icehockey.zip</path>
        <name>Ice Hockey (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The play and mechanics of Ice Hockey are mostly similar to that of ice hockey in real life. The objective for both team is to hit a black puck with a hockey stick that each player carries into the opponent's goal. Teams are made up of five players including the goaltender, as opposed to six in real life. Players wear ice skates, which are used to skate across the icy arena. Each game is made up of three periods, with the victory going to the team who has the most points at the end of the game. At the beginning, two opposing players from each team face off in the middle of the rink. There are three kinds of players - the first is fast, weak, and feeble, but is good at the face-off; the second is average in all qualities, and the third is slow and poor at the face-off, but very powerful, both in body checking and shooting strength. The arena is similarly designed to a real-world ice hockey arena. The arena is coated in ice, with a goal on either side of the arena. There are a variety of marked areas, including the goal line that the puck must cross to score, the attacking/defending zone which is situated closely to each goal, the face-off spot, the neutral spot, and others. Each side of the arena has exactly the same design. If two opposing players fight for the puck for a certain amount of time, other players join into the fight, resulting in the player from the losing team in the fight to be put in the penalty box for a period of time.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Sports / Hockey</genre>
        <genreid>2933</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/icehockey.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/icehockey.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1612475080">
        <path>ishidouj.zip</path>
        <name>Ishidou (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Ishido is a puzzle board game consisting of a set of 72 stones and a game board of 96 squares.

Every stone has two attributes: a color and a symbol. There are six colors and six symbols in each stone set, thus creating 36 unique stones. Since each stone comes in a pair, there are therefore 72 stones in each stone set.

The primary objective of Ishido is to place all 72 stones onto the board of 96 squares. The challenge arises because stones must be placed adjacent to others that they match, either by color or symbol. When the board begins to fill up, this objective is not so easily accomplished.

A valuable move is the 4-way, in which a stone is placed in the midst of four others, two of which are matched by color, and two which are matched by symbol.

Ishido comes with 6 differently themed stone sets, 5 different game boards, and a variety of Oriental chimes and sound effects.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="2215">Software Resources International</developer>
        <publisher id="20239">Hiro</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>ishidou.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/ishidou.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/ishidou.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="985411126">
        <path>ishidou.zip</path>
        <name>Ishidou (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>Ishido is a puzzle board game consisting of a set of 72 stones and a game board of 96 squares.

Every stone has two attributes: a color and a symbol. There are six colors and six symbols in each stone set, thus creating 36 unique stones. Since each stone comes in a pair, there are therefore 72 stones in each stone set.

The primary objective of Ishido is to place all 72 stones onto the board of 96 squares. The challenge arises because stones must be placed adjacent to others that they match, either by color or symbol. When the board begins to fill up, this objective is not so easily accomplished.

A valuable move is the 4-way, in which a stone is placed in the midst of four others, two of which are matched by color, and two which are matched by symbol.

Ishido comes with 6 differently themed stone sets, 5 different game boards, and a variety of Oriental chimes and sound effects.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="2215">Software Resources International</developer>
        <publisher id="20239">Hiro</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/ishidou.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/ishidou.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2488819848">
        <path>jikaishometmag.zip</path>
        <name>Jikai Shounen Met Mag (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The player must go around each stage and collect every sphere in order to progress. Each sphere can change the polarity of the character from red to blue and vice versa. Each stage is littered with blue and red arrows: Being the same color as these arrows will magnetize the player character, which has different effects depending on the direction the arrow is pointing: For instance, an arrow pointing down will push the player to the ground if they are the reverse color but a same-colored character can hover across as the blocks will hold them up. Conversely, an arrow pointing up will allow players of the opposite color to jump far higher from the arrow, but will almost entirely eliminate the jumping power of a same-colored character as it pulls them down.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="506">Thinking Rabbit</developer>
        <publisher id="20237">Disk Original Group (DOG)</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/jikaishometmag.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/jikaishometmag.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2232320663">
        <path>kaettmarbro.zip</path>
        <name>Kaettekita Mario Brothers (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="3315285346">
        <path>kalinnotsurugij.zip</path>
        <name>Kalin no Tsurugi (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Monsters have appeared in the once peaceful land of Alitania, and the people have fallen into terror. The king's orders have fallen upon you, the bravest knight of Alitania.

"The fate of the country hangs by a thread. It may be possible to save the country with Gladrif's magic, but he is nowhere to be found. Therefore, I want you to search for him! Find Gladrif, defeat the monsters, and restore peace to this land once again!"</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="10815">Xtalsoft</developer>
        <publisher id="20237">Disk Original Group (DOG)</publisher>
        <genre>Role playing games</genre>
        <genreid>8</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>kalinnotsurugi.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/kalinnotsurugi.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/kalinnotsurugi.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="681358288">
        <path>kalinnotsurugi.zip</path>
        <name>Kalin no Tsurugi (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>Monsters have appeared in the once peaceful land of Alitania, and the people have fallen into terror. The king's orders have fallen upon you, the bravest knight of Alitania.

"The fate of the country hangs by a thread. It may be possible to save the country with Gladrif's magic, but he is nowhere to be found. Therefore, I want you to search for him! Find Gladrif, defeat the monsters, and restore peace to this land once again!"</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="10815">Xtalsoft</developer>
        <publisher id="20237">Disk Original Group (DOG)</publisher>
        <genre>Role playing games</genre>
        <genreid>8</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/kalinnotsurugi.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/kalinnotsurugi.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="15405547">
        <path>kamenridbla.zip</path>
        <name>Kamen Rider Black - Taiketsu Shadow Moon (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The game is based on the Kamen Rider Black television series, which was the eight installment of the Kamen Rider superhero series.In the game, players take control of Kamen Rider Black, who must defeat numerous Gorgom mutants. There are five levels of four stages each. In the first four levels, players must complete three side scrolling stages with a boss at the end. In the fourth stage, the player must fight against a final level boss using a zoomed in perspective with larger sprites. The player gets to ride Battle Hopper motorcycle throughout the second and fourth levels. The fifth level is composed entirely of boss fights, first against three Evil Lords, and then against Shadow Moon. If the player loses against Shadow Moon, the bad ending is shown before the game ends.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="437">Human</developer>
        <publisher id="580">Bandai Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/kamenridbla.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/kamenridbla.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2577477393">
        <path>kickandrun.zip</path>
        <name>Kick and Run (Japan)</name>
        <desc>A soccer game based on the arcade game of the same name.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="55">Taito</developer>
        <publisher id="55">Taito</publisher>
        <genre>Sports / Soccer</genre>
        <genreid>2847</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/kickandrun.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/kickandrun.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1783262826">
        <path>kickcha.zip</path>
        <name>Kick Challenger - Air Foot (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="644110745">
        <path>kietaprincess.zip</path>
        <name>Kieta Princess (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The Kingdom of Rabia's princess goes missing during a visit to Japan, surrounding the investigation of the medicine to an "epidemic dementia," known as "Oninofuguri", and the prevention of its importing. The player takes the role of a detective determined to unravel the mystery of the missing princess Kilala, in this RPG style adventure game. Yasuko Tomita served as the model of one of the characters. Certain telephone numbers would appear, which, if called, would provide the player with a hint, spoken by Yasuko Tomita.

In order to track down Kobayashi, the criminal protagonist, you must visit five different towns and collect information. Neary every house and building can be entered, which was unique for its time. The game also features a high degree of freedom, allowing you to visit restaurants for a bite, or a Dojo to train, or to hunt for vegetation to sell for money, while you are looking for the princess.

Another introduced concept that was novel for its time was the notion of day and night changing the appearance of the city. During the evening, you may encounter a street gang, and they may open fire on you, although you can defend yourself with a revolver. However, if over 20 innocent people are gunned down, you will be arrested and sent to the police station where you must pay a fine and return to the starting point.

The degree of difficult throughout the game is considered quite high, with very few hints to help you out, while other hints are misleading. For example, one hint suggests that you if you sleep over night at a particular crossroad in a city, you will get a key item, but this hint is false. Although you are supposedly a detective, you never actually get to accuse anyone of a crime.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="466">Imagineer</developer>
        <publisher id="26824">Wave Jack</publisher>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>13</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/kietaprincess.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/kietaprincess.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1412109492">
        <path>kikikai.zip</path>
        <name>Kiki Kaikai - Dotou Hen (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="3332439783">
        <path>kinni.zip</path>
        <name>Kinnikuman - Kinnikusei Oui Soudatsusen (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Kinnikuman - Kinnikusei Oui Soudatsusen is a wrestling game based on the popular toy line, manga and anime about a klutzy superhero who fights most of his opponents with professional wrestling moves. The first Kinnikuman game (released as M.U.S.C.L.E. in the US) was a straightforward wrestling game, but this sequel changes the action to a side-scrolling action brawler game with additional RPG and story elements. The main character can still use wrestling moves on enemies, but most of the attacks are simple punches and kicks.Curiously, the boss music is a sped up version of "In-A-Gadda-Da-Vida" by Iron Butterfly.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="580">Bandai Namco</developer>
        <publisher id="580">Bandai Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Sports</genre>
        <genreid>685</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/kinni.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/kinni.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2526799235">
        <path>knighlor.zip</path>
        <name>Knight Lore - Majou no Ookami Otoko (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Knight Lore is a a 3D isometric adventure game by Jaleco, originally released by the British game company Ultimate. Saberman, the hero of the game, has been cursed by an evil wizard. Every night, he turns into a creepy werewolf and he is on a journey to retrieve all the necessary ingredients to create a magic potion. This potion, he hopes, will get him to return to his human shape. The game starts in a dark forest, somewhere in there the wizard awaits for the potion's ingredients such as diamonds, bottles etc... Our hero's task is to wander around and find them, one at the time, and bring them back to him. But our hero must watch out, he turns into a werewolf at night and the wizard won't hesitate to use his magic against him. Saberman must make sure to always approach him as a human. Up to three items can be carried at the same time, they can also be dropped on the ground and climbed to reach higher platforms. However, once a new ingredient is delivered to the wizard, our hero leaves empty handed and lose all stored items. Series of enemies and hazards are of course scattered along his path, such as spirits, spikes or pits. Once all the ingredients are collected, the game jumps to another location where more objects need to be found with meaner hazards and enemies. This is also the point where the player's progress can be saved.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="541">TOSE</developer>
        <publisher id="293">Jaleco</publisher>
        <genre>Action / Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>3566</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/knighlor.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/knighlor.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3081012261">
        <path>knightmovej.zip</path>
        <name>Knight Move (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The game is based around the concept of how a knight piece is moved in the game of chess. The player controls a knight chess piece that is constantly jumping and must continually choose which of the possible legal moves to make before the knight lands back on the board.

When the knight lands on any square on the board, it turns from white to light teal. Landing there again, turns it dark teal. Landing there yet again destroys the square altogether, leaving a hole that the player must avoid. Falling in a hole will result in a game over. Consecutively creating several holes results in a chain increasing the player's score in differing increments.

At the beginning of each "round", a heart is placed somewhere on the board. A heart (or multiple hearts) must be collected to advance to the next round, which thereby replaces all holes on the board with new white squares and places a new heart somewhere on the board. Depending on the game mode, hearts will sometimes move themselves every few jumps of the knight.

The player can also gather a small amount of extra points, at any time, by holding the A button and speeding up the knight's movement. The main objective in Knight Move is to continue this cycle, despite the increasing game speed, and reach the highest score possible.

The game also includes a simultaneous 2 player versus mode similar to the single player modes.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="12323">JV Dialog</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>knightmove.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/knightmove.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/knightmove.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2897535024">
        <path>knightmove.zip</path>
        <name>Knight Move (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>The game is based around the concept of how a knight piece is moved in the game of chess. The player controls a knight chess piece that is constantly jumping and must continually choose which of the possible legal moves to make before the knight lands back on the board.

When the knight lands on any square on the board, it turns from white to light teal. Landing there again, turns it dark teal. Landing there yet again destroys the square altogether, leaving a hole that the player must avoid. Falling in a hole will result in a game over. Consecutively creating several holes results in a chain increasing the player's score in differing increments.

At the beginning of each "round", a heart is placed somewhere on the board. A heart (or multiple hearts) must be collected to advance to the next round, which thereby replaces all holes on the board with new white squares and places a new heart somewhere on the board. Depending on the game mode, hearts will sometimes move themselves every few jumps of the knight.

The player can also gather a small amount of extra points, at any time, by holding the A button and speeding up the knight's movement. The main objective in Knight Move is to continue this cycle, despite the increasing game speed, and reach the highest score possible.

The game also includes a simultaneous 2 player versus mode similar to the single player modes.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="12323">JV Dialog</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/knightmove.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/knightmove.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1963680309">
        <path>konamictennis.zip</path>
        <name>Konamic Tennis (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Konamic Tennis is part of a long line of Konami sports games made specifically for the Famicom and its Famicom Disk System peripheral, which had previously used the term "Exciting" to signify its Konami status: As is the case with games such as Exciting Baseball or Exciting Basketball (known in the west as Double Dribble). Instead, this and future Konami sports games for the system would have the "Konamic" appellation; a portmanteau of "Konami" and "dynamic". At least, this is how the same pun in its original Japanese is commonly transliterated.

Konamic Tennis follows a similar design philosophy as other tennis games at the time (and would be used for most of the ones to follow) by depicting the action from behind the serving player's side of the court. It follows the rules of the sport precisely, with a single game usually ending after four successful volleys (scored as 15, 30, 40 and Game) and the first to win six games deciding a set. Players can choose between a single set match or a longer 3-set match. They can also play in a tournament or a single one-on-one game with a CPU (or human) opponent of their choosing.

One feature Konamic Tennis introduces to the genre is that of the serving view, shown as an inset whenever a player serves the ball to start a game. The goal is to hit the ball at precisely the right moment to serve an excellent shot; too early or too late will cause the player to either hit the net or send the ball too far, or simply not hit the ball at all. In all these cases, it counts as a foul and the player has one more chance to correctly serve the ball, otherwise points are awarded to the opponent.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Sports / Tennis</genre>
        <genreid>2867</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/konamictennis.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/konamictennis.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2732414189">
        <path>konekmon.zip</path>
        <name>Koneko Monogatari - The Adventures of Chatran (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="934510665">
        <path>linknobouj.zip</path>
        <name>Link no Bouken - The Legend of Zelda 2 (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Link no Bouken - The Legend of Zelda 2 is the second installment in The Legend of Zelda series, published by Nintendo for the Nintendo Entertainment System. It was originally released in Japan on the Famicom Disk System less than a year after the release of The Legend of Zelda. 

The Adventure of Link is a direct sequel to the original The Legend of Zelda, and again involves the protagonist Link on a quest to save Princess Zelda -- who is not the same Princess from the first game, but another member of the royal family by the same name, who was placed under a sleeping spell a long time ago. The Adventure of Link's emphasis on side-scrolling and RPG-style elements, however, was a significant departure from its predecessor and has given it a reputation as the "black sheep" of the Zelda series. It is arguably the hardest Zelda game. Despite this reputation, the game was highly successful and introduced many elements that would become commonplace in future Zelda games.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Role playing games</genre>
        <genreid>8</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>linknobou.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/linknobou.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/linknobou.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2820704640">
        <path>linknobouc.zip</path>
        <name>Link no Bouken - The Legend of Zelda 2 (Japan) (Rev 1) - Castellano v1.0</name>
        <desc>Link no Bouken - The Legend of Zelda 2 is the second installment in The Legend of Zelda series, published by Nintendo for the Nintendo Entertainment System. It was originally released in Japan on the Famicom Disk System less than a year after the release of The Legend of Zelda. 

The Adventure of Link is a direct sequel to the original The Legend of Zelda, and again involves the protagonist Link on a quest to save Princess Zelda -- who is not the same Princess from the first game, but another member of the royal family by the same name, who was placed under a sleeping spell a long time ago. The Adventure of Link's emphasis on side-scrolling and RPG-style elements, however, was a significant departure from its predecessor and has given it a reputation as the "black sheep" of the Zelda series. It is arguably the hardest Zelda game. Despite this reputation, the game was highly successful and introduced many elements that would become commonplace in future Zelda games.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Role playing games</genre>
        <genreid>8</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>linknobou.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/linknobou.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/linknobou.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="472982999">
        <path>linknobou.zip</path>
        <name>Link no Bouken - The Legend of Zelda 2 (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>Link no Bouken - The Legend of Zelda 2 is the second installment in The Legend of Zelda series, published by Nintendo for the Nintendo Entertainment System. It was originally released in Japan on the Famicom Disk System less than a year after the release of The Legend of Zelda. 

The Adventure of Link is a direct sequel to the original The Legend of Zelda, and again involves the protagonist Link on a quest to save Princess Zelda -- who is not the same Princess from the first game, but another member of the royal family by the same name, who was placed under a sleeping spell a long time ago. The Adventure of Link's emphasis on side-scrolling and RPG-style elements, however, was a significant departure from its predecessor and has given it a reputation as the "black sheep" of the Zelda series. It is arguably the hardest Zelda game. Despite this reputation, the game was highly successful and introduced many elements that would become commonplace in future Zelda games.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Role playing games</genre>
        <genreid>8</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/linknobou.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/linknobou.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="864547782">
        <path>lutter.zip</path>
        <name>Lutter (Japan)</name>
        <desc>A side scrolling adventure game where you must rescue a maiden from the dungeon of an evil force. You'll navigate the dungeon and can fight and take damage from monsters by bumping into them. You will also come across keys to use for doors.</desc>
        <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="515">Athena</developer>
        <publisher id="515">Athena</publisher>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>13</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/lutter.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/lutter.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3702044123">
        <path>maerchenveil.zip</path>
        <name>Maerchen Veil (Japan)</name>
        <desc>A long time ago, people from Ferikusu could communicate with the gods and divine spirits. The king of the kingdom is now looking for a young man to marry his daughter, the royal princess. Many contestants are selected and a tournament is organized to decide of the new prince. However, before the end or the ceremony, an evil magician sends the last hero, the one the princess has fallen in love with, to an unknown and desolated world. He also quickly realizes that he fell under a terrible curse, and he has been turned into a weird creature. The only item he has left is a magic bracelet the princess gave him. The player takes control of the lost prince and his journey will take him back to where he came from, confront the evil magician and marry the princess he loves. Each stage starts with a short animation (called a "visual stage") which unfolds the story as the game progresses. The rest of the game follows a classic top-view action formula, where the hero defeats all kind of enemies with the help of his magic powers. Sometimes, special items can be found under tree logs or rocks.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="151">System Sacom</developer>
        <publisher id="37">Sunsoft</publisher>
        <genre>Role playing games</genre>
        <genreid>8</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/maerchenveil.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/maerchenveil.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1684405027">
        <path>magmapro.zip</path>
        <name>Magma Project - Hacker (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Magma Project Hacker is a sci-fi themed RPG and an adaptation of the 1985 PC/Amiga/Atari ST strategy game Hacker. As with the Famicom Disk System adaptation of Monty on the Run, a considerable number of liberties were taken with the game's themes practically transforming it into a completely different game. Ironically, the story more closely resembles another western PC game, Captive, with its plot.
The player character witnesses a murder and is told to seek information on a shadowy organization known as the Magma Project by the dying victim. In order to effectively hunt for clues, the player character uses a device to activate a robot on the other side of the planet and employs the robot's various combat and exploration functions to track down the Magma Project.</desc>
        <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8802">Bits Laboratory</developer>
        <publisher id="8763">Tokuma Shoten</publisher>
        <genre>Role playing games</genre>
        <genreid>8</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/magmapro.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/magmapro.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2509433628">
        <path>matounohou.zip</path>
        <name>Matou no Houkai - The Hero of Babel (Japan)</name>
        <desc>During the height of Babylonian civilization, people built the Tower of Babel in an attempt to reach god. God sees this, and becomes angry with mankind's hubris. He rains thunder down upon the tower to drive people away. In order to keep people away from the tower, god fills it up with giant creatures and evil spiritsnnSeveral thousands of years later, the strongest devil Asmodeous gains control over all of the creatures and spirits that god placed in the tower. He attacks the neighboring towns, and steals all of their golden and silver treasures, as well as the most beautiful maiden in the land.
Your mission of salvation is to rescue the maiden, and destroy the cursed tower in order to return peace to the world.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26823">Carry Soft</developer>
        <publisher id="2870">Pony Canyon</publisher>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>13</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/matounohou.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/matounohou.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="625954469">
        <path>meikyjiidabj.zip</path>
        <name>Meikyuu Jiin Dababa (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The game takes place in India, where a young man's significant-other is kidnapped by an evil wizard. He must then tackle the four areas of the labyrinth temple of Dababa to rescue her.

In order to accomplish this task, the player cannot simple move across the floor. Rather, the player and all of the enemies hop from one square tile to another, throughout the game. In a majority of stages, the player must uncover the seals which will unlock the door to the next stage by leaping on to the particular tiles which keep the seals concealed. Not every door will take the player forward, however, as some doors are trick doors that may take the player to a previous stage. In some stages, the player must simply survive the onslaught of enemies, while in others, the player is racing against the clock.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>meikyjiidab.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/meikyjiidab.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/meikyjiidab.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2834202084">
        <path>meikyjiidab.zip</path>
        <name>Meikyuu Jiin Dababa (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>The game takes place in India, where a young man's significant-other is kidnapped by an evil wizard. He must then tackle the four areas of the labyrinth temple of Dababa to rescue her.

In order to accomplish this task, the player cannot simple move across the floor. Rather, the player and all of the enemies hop from one square tile to another, throughout the game. In a majority of stages, the player must uncover the seals which will unlock the door to the next stage by leaping on to the particular tiles which keep the seals concealed. Not every door will take the player forward, however, as some doors are trick doors that may take the player to a previous stage. In some stages, the player must simply survive the onslaught of enemies, while in others, the player is racing against the clock.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/meikyjiidab.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/meikyjiidab.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3200195396">
        <path>metroidj.zip</path>
        <name>Metroid (Japan)</name>
        <desc>It's you against the evil Mother Brain in the thrilling battle of Metroid! You're inside the fortress planet Zebes. The planet of endless secret passageways where the Metroid are multiplying. Left alone the Metroid are harmless. But in the wrong hands they could destroy the galaxy. It's up to you to prevent the Mother Brain that controls Zebes from using the Metroid for evil purposes. But that won't be easy. You'll have to use your spacesuit to absorb valuable energy for your search to gain the use of power items like the Ice Beam, Wave Beam, High Jump Boots and Varia. If you survive, it will be you and your acquired powers against the Mother Brain.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>13</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>metroid.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/metroid.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/metroid.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="154543618">
        <path>metroid.zip</path>
        <name>Metroid (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>It's you against the evil Mother Brain in the thrilling battle of Metroid! You're inside the fortress planet Zebes. The planet of endless secret passageways where the Metroid are multiplying. Left alone the Metroid are harmless. But in the wrong hands they could destroy the galaxy. It's up to you to prevent the Mother Brain that controls Zebes from using the Metroid for evil purposes. But that won't be easy. You'll have to use your spacesuit to absorb valuable energy for your search to gain the use of power items like the Ice Beam, Wave Beam, High Jump Boots and Varia. If you survive, it will be you and your acquired powers against the Mother Brain.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>13</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/metroid.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/metroid.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1186393882">
        <path>michaengdai.zip</path>
        <name>Michael English Daibouken (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Michael English Daibouken (lit: "Michael's English Grand Adventure") is an educational game where the character of Michael, an orange cat, teaches kittens the various letters in the English language as well as some English vocabulary. Michael has to catch floating letters in order to spell out English words, while avoiding the incorrect letters. The game has various different backdrops, including space.

The character of Michael comes from the Japanese serial manga strip "What's Michael", created by Makoto Kobayashi which might be considered analogous to Garfield, due to them both being orange cats. It varies between observing goofy pet behavior to more abstract tales of fantasy with anthropomorphized versions of the animal characters.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="12324">Scorpion Soft</developer>
        <publisher id="12324">Scorpion Soft</publisher>
        <genre>Educational</genre>
        <genreid>30</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/michaengdai.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/michaengdai.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="133575495">
        <path>moerotwi.zip</path>
        <name>Moero TwinBee - Cinnamon Hakase wo Sukue! (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Moero TwinBee can be played by up to three player simultaneously: the first two players control TwinBee and WinBee (the ships from the previous game) using the standard Famicom controllers, whereas the third player controls GwinBee (a green ship) by connecting an additional controller into the console's expansion port. Unlike the original TwinBee, which only featured vertical-scrolling stages, Stinger adds side-scrolling stages to the mix as well. There are seven stages in the game. Stage 1, 3, and 7 are side-scrolling stages, while the rest are vertical-scrolling stages. The controls remain the same between the two styles of gameplay, with the only difference being that in the side-scrolling segments, the A button shoots hearts over the ship instead of dropping bombs into the ground like the vertical-scrolling segments, which helps the player keep the power-up bells afloat in the side-scrolling stages.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
        <genreid>79</genreid>
        <players>1-3</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/moerotwi.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/moerotwi.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1610631624">
        <path>montyonrunj.zip</path>
        <name>Monty on the Run - Monty no Doki Doki Dai Dassou (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <cloneof>montyonrun.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="3154888974">
        <path>montyonrun.zip</path>
        <name>Monty on the Run - Monty no Doki Doki Dai Dassou (T-Eng)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="48914518">
        <path>moonballmagic.zip</path>
        <name>Moonball Magic (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The game starts out by depositing the pinball in the middle of a simulated pinball table. However, once the ball is shot into one of the holes on the play field, the game enters an elaborate intro sequence which the player can control. The game contains 11 stages, each of which contain a target hole that the player must hit the ball into in order to advance to the next stage. The stages get more elaborate, and more moving obstacles appear to interfere with the behavior of the ball. In addition to controlling the flippers, the control pad can also be used to "nudge" the ball in either direction, although the effectiveness of this varies.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="151">System Sacom</developer>
        <publisher id="20237">Disk Original Group (DOG)</publisher>
        <genre>Pinball</genre>
        <genreid>31</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/moonballmagic.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/moonballmagic.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="17914108">
        <path>mystemurcas.zip</path>
        <name>Mysterious Murasame Castle (T-Eng)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="794455796">
        <path>nazonokab.zip</path>
        <name>Nazo no Kabe - Block Kuzushi (Japan)</name>
        <desc>In the year 30XX, the mankind has exhausted all the metal resources on the Earth, so they had to travel into space in order to find more. They find a planet high in minerals, and they name it Selim.

But soon they discover that there is someone watching, spying on them; it's some kind of alien race. These aliens find a hole in the humans' main computer and get inside it. The computer, programmed to self-destruct in case of a failure, starts its countdown.

There is only one way to avoid self-destruction, which is entering a 14 digit code into the machine; but these digits are hidden in the walls of the corridors in the complex. Your mission is to find these letters and avoid self-destruction, aboard the "Red Warrior", and using your only weapon, an energy ball.

Nazo no Kabe - Block Kuzushi  is an Arkanoid clone for the NES, but it's probably one of the most singular clones. You'll have to destroy all blocks but also the walls surrounding them, as the 14 letters are spread inside them, apart from killing the alien bosses here and there. In your way, you will find a bizarre mixture of enemies, from alien forms to parts of the body (eyes, lips, skulls...), who will make your game tougher by changing the direction of your ball; but also happier by dropping a sweet variety of power-ups such as the cherries (extra life), the clock (the enemies freeze), a rocket (to throw into the blocks), a fire device (the ball fires missiles), a parachute (slows the ball) an extra ball, or the weirdest of them all, the so-called Konami Man, who will take you to a secret parallel complex with different (and harder) levels.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/nazonokab.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/nazonokab.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4155776228">
        <path>nazonomur.zip</path>
        <name>Nazo no Murasamejou (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <cloneof>mystemurcas.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="3132935057">
        <path>otocky.zip</path>
        <name>Otocky (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Otocky can be described as a musical side-scrolling shoot 'em up. The player's spaceship has a ball for a weapon, which can be fired in eight directions; each direction corresponds to a different musical note. The note plays when the player presses the fire button, and is also quantized in time so that it matches the beat playing in the background. By using the weapon selectively the player can improvise music while playing.

Otocky is notable for being one of the first games that include creative/procedural generative music.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="32982">Scitron</developer>
        <publisher id="2872">ASCII Corporation</publisher>
        <genre>Shooter</genre>
        <genreid>2646</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/otocky.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/otocky.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1629049186">
        <path>patla.zip</path>
        <name>Patlabor - The Mobile Police - Dai 2 Shoutai Shutsudou Seyo! (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Patlabor - The Mobile Police - Dai 2 Shoutai Shutsudou Seyo is an action-platformer-shooter game from Bandai and yet another licensed game from the publishing giant. In this case, it is an adaptation of the anime and manga of the same name.

Patlabor is a portmanteau of "patrol" and "labor", with labor being the common name for technologically advanced mechanical walkers used by various construction companies to perform heavy-duty work that a human wouldn't be capable of achieving on their own. Because more and more of these labors are being hijacked by criminals, an equally powerful force of police-issued labors are commissioned and manned by members of the police force. The show follows Section 2 of the Mobile Police Patlabor division in particular.

The game is divided between side-scrolling platformer/run-and-gun levels and first-person shooter modes in which the player character, in their patlabor, must keep the peace by subduing criminals and other villains, some of which have their own labors.</desc>
        <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="2913">Advance Communication Company</developer>
        <publisher id="580">Bandai Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Shooter / 1st person</genre>
        <genreid>3024</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/patla.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/patla.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1168110593">
        <path>progolsarkagnoto.zip</path>
        <name>Pro Golfer Saru - Kage no Tournament (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Pro Golfer Saru: Kage no Tournament is a golf game with fantasy elements thrown in, developed by Bandai and published on the Family Computer Disk System in 1987. The game is based on a manga (Japanese comic book) known as Pro Golfer Saru published by Fujiko Fujio (also responsible for Doraemon) about a young cave man or neanderthal-like boy who desires to become the greatest golfer in history. To accomplish this goal, he trains in the most desolate of locations, driving golf balls over giant chasms in an effort to hit greens several hundred meters away.

The game is composed of a training mode as well as the tournament challenge. The first nine holes replicate the desolate, and almost prehistoric locations that Saru normally trains in. Balls must be driven over wide spaces in order to stay in bounds and continue play. The back nine holes take place is a more modern, and even slightly futuristic locale, where Saru must sink balls from across rooftops. The game will save one players performance to disk. It was never released outside of Japan.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="541">TOSE</developer>
        <publisher id="580">Bandai Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Sports / Golf</genre>
        <genreid>2913</genreid>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/progolsarkagnoto.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/progolsarkagnoto.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1421395818">
        <path>puttputtgolf.zip</path>
        <name>Putt Putt Golf (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Putt Putt Golf by Pack-In-Video is one of many golf games for the Famicom and the Famicom Disk System, but one of the few to take players through an abstract world rather than an approximation of a real golf course. The goal of each stage is to reach the hole on the green and pot the ball in as few strokes as possible, but each of the courses are covered with various obstacles - some animated, some stationary. The player must navigate around them (or use them to their advantage, in some cases) in order to achieve the best score.</desc>
        <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="17379">Pack In Video</developer>
        <publisher id="17379">Pack In Video</publisher>
        <genre>Sports / Golf</genre>
        <genreid>2913</genreid>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/puttputtgolf.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/puttputtgolf.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3339374514">
        <path>puzzleboysj.zip</path>
        <name>Puzzle Boys (Japan)</name>
        <desc>A puzzle game in which you must control a potato character and navigate mazes by pushing blocks and solving puzzles to rescue his vegetable friends in a deep labyrinth.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="264">Atlus</developer>
        <publisher id="264">Atlus</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>puzzleboys.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/puzzleboys.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/puzzleboys.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2613151369">
        <path>puzzleboys.zip</path>
        <name>Puzzle Boys (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>A puzzle game in which you must control a potato character and navigate mazes by pushing blocks and solving puzzles to rescue his vegetable friends in a deep labyrinth.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="264">Atlus</developer>
        <publisher id="264">Atlus</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/puzzleboys.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/puzzleboys.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1769819592">
        <path>radicbomjirkun.zip</path>
        <name>Radical Bomber!! Jirai-kun (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Radical Bomber!! Jirai-kun FDS is a strategy game developed and published by Jaleco for the Famicom Disk System in 1988. The environment of the game resembles a giant board game where each player moves from one space to another. The goal of Radical Bomber is to carefully think out a plan of action and find a way to trap the opponents by removing connections between each "square" on the map. Successfully isolating an opponent from the rest of the board causes them to forfeit the game. If you manage to isolate every every opponent, Jirai-kun will advance the next level. This game was only released in Japan, and has never been translated from its original Japanese language.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="293">Jaleco</developer>
        <publisher id="293">Jaleco</publisher>
        <genre>Strategy</genre>
        <genreid>27</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/radicbomjirkun.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/radicbomjirkun.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1818506781">
        <path>reflectworld.zip</path>
        <name>Reflect World (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Reflect World is a hybrid RPG/Shooter developed by East Cube for the Family Computer Disk System. It is the only game developed by East Cube for any console.

You fly around a planet collecting various items to advance to different areas.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="17347">East Cube</developer>
        <publisher id="17347">East Cube</publisher>
        <genre>Shooter</genre>
        <genreid>2646</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/reflectworld.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/reflectworld.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="468085802">
        <path>relics.zip</path>
        <name>Relics - Ankoku Yousai (Japan)</name>
        <desc>At some point in the early history of earth, the forces of darkness known as HELL were at war with the forces of light known as HEAVEN, and the took this battle to our planet. The HELL forces quickly enslaved human beings, and the earth was cast in darkness and despair. Somewhere on the planet, a fortress was built to harness the power of the sun in order to defeat the forces of HELL, should they ever come to our planet, but it fell into ruin after centuries of neglect. The Shining Princess of HEAVEN was captured and imprisoned on the top floor of this fortress. Also inside are the spirits of the Holy Warriors of Light who have the power to defeat the forces of HELL. However, they are asleep and unable to awaken. Earth's only hope is you, a being who has sacrificed his body in order to inhabit the fallen bodies of the departed. To succeed, you must use each body to obtain the key words which are found in, and used to open, the dungeons of the fortress.
Relics: Ankoku Yosai (Lit. "Relics: Darkness Fort") is an action-adventure game developed by Bothtec for play on the Family Computer Disk System and published in 1987. It is somewhat related to, but entirely different from, a game known as Relics which was released on several popular Japanese home computer formats, including the MSX. In the game, you control a spirit who has the ability to enhabit the body of certain defeated enemies, effectively powering up by inhabiting the body of stronger foes.
</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="10731">Bothtec</developer>
        <publisher id="10731">Bothtec</publisher>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>13</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/relics.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/relics.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2190258382">
        <path>replicart.zip</path>
        <name>Replicart (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The game takes place at the end of the 21st century. A gigantic snake-like alien called Sonada invades Earth and constructs a base under the soil. Sonada attacks various locations, stealing precious resources, and appears invulnerable to all forms of modern offenses. Engineers regroup and construct a base where a new weapon can be developed. They create the Replicart in the image of Sonada, and give it the power to convert resources into new material that can extend the Replicart and increase its strength until it reaches enough power to destroy the invader.

Replicart is to the original Snake game what Arkanoid is to Breakout; an upgrade that takes the core features of the game and expands upon them by adding enemies, power-ups and more elaborate play settings. In it you must move a robotic snake through mazes in an effort to collect a required number of pieces before the exit will open. The snake's length extends by one unit for every piece collected. If the snake's head touches any of the walls, enemies or its own body, it is destroyed and the player loses one life.

The conversion to the Famicom Disk System by Taito is quite different than the MSX2 original. The number of levels has been reduced to 100, but between every 10 levels, a boss battle occurs in which the player must chase a monster around the screen and blast it until the monster takes enough damage. A bonus level is provided for the player after each boss is defeated before they progress to the next level.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="772">Dual</developer>
        <publisher id="55">Taito</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/replicart.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/replicart.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1202547092">
        <path>rogerrabbit.zip</path>
        <name>Roger Rabbit (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Help Roger Rabbit collect hearts in various levels and save Jessica Rabbit while avoiding the dastardly weasels! This was eventually released in the US as Bugs Bunny's Crazy Castle and changed the hearts to carrots and the weasels into various characters from Looney Tunes. This was due to Kemco losing the rights to Roger Rabbit in the US.

While presented in a side-scroller format, Roger Rabbit differed from standard side-scrollers such as Super Mario Bros. in that Roger Rabbit did not have a jump function; therefore, only by taking different routes could Roger avoid enemies. Some of the levels had boxing gloves, invincibility potions, safes, crates, flower pots, or ten-pound weights that could be used against the enemies in the game. As a result, the game had a "puzzle-solving" atmosphere.

Players score 100 points for every carrot with the last one in each floor giving the player an extra life, 100 points for every enemy defeated using invincibility bottles, 500 points per enemy using boxing glove and 1000 points per enemy that gets hit with heavy objects.</desc>
        <releasedate>19890101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="462">Kemco</developer>
        <publisher id="462">Kemco</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/rogerrabbit.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/rogerrabbit.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3218785512">
        <path>sdgunworgacsescwa.zip</path>
        <name>SD Gundam World - Gachapon Senshi - Scramble Wars (Japan)</name>
        <desc>SD Gundam World Gachapon Senshi - Scramble Wars is a hybrid strategy/action game based on the popular Gundam toy series from Japan. It was developed and published by Bandai for the Famicom Disk System. Two different versions were released within two months of one another. The initial version was sold in stores for ¥3,300 at the end of 1987 on its own disk with a case. The second version was sold for a much cheaper ¥500 in the beginning of 1988 as part of the "Disk Writer" system, where players could bring their own blank disks to a kiosk and have a game of their choice written to the disk. While both versions contain 10 maps to play on, the Disk Writer edition replaces five of the maps from the original edition with new designs. "Gachapon Senshi" means toy capsule warrior, as the gachapon toy capsule was a popular format for fans of the series to buy super-deformed versions of their favorite Gundam characters.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="580">Bandai Namco</developer>
        <publisher id="580">Bandai Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Strategy</genre>
        <genreid>27</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/sdgunworgacsescwa.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/sdgunworgacsescwa.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3068833054">
        <path>sdgunworgacsescwac.zip</path>
        <name>SD Gundam World - Gachapon Senshi - Scramble Wars (Japan) [b] - Castellano v1.0</name>
        <desc>SD Gundam World Gachapon Senshi - Scramble Wars is a hybrid strategy/action game based on the popular Gundam toy series from Japan. It was developed and published by Bandai for the Famicom Disk System. Two different versions were released within two months of one another. The initial version was sold in stores for ¥3,300 at the end of 1987 on its own disk with a case. The second version was sold for a much cheaper ¥500 in the beginning of 1988 as part of the "Disk Writer" system, where players could bring their own blank disks to a kiosk and have a game of their choice written to the disk. While both versions contain 10 maps to play on, the Disk Writer edition replaces five of the maps from the original edition with new designs. "Gachapon Senshi" means toy capsule warrior, as the gachapon toy capsule was a popular format for fans of the series to buy super-deformed versions of their favorite Gundam characters.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="580">Bandai Namco</developer>
        <publisher id="580">Bandai Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Strategy</genre>
        <genreid>27</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <cloneof>sdgunworgacsescwa.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/sdgunworgacsescwa.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/sdgunworgacsescwa.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1492545318">
        <path>sectionz.zip</path>
        <name>Section-Z (Japan)</name>
        <desc>An enemy space fortress of the Balangool Empire is approaching Earth. Captain Commando has to infiltrate it and find his way to Section-Z to destroy L-Brain, the computer controlling the fortress.
Secton-Z is a side-scrolling game in which the player is a space soldier who can land on the ground and other platform structures and run along them. It is one of the first games which gives players the ability to not only shoot forward, but backwards. It is also one of the first games to give players a choice of paths at the end of each level. Depending on which path they took, they could get special weapons or bombs which wouldn't show up if the other path was taken. To compensate for this, the path without the weapon is often easier. They can activate these special weapons by pressing Select.
Sometimes, one of the paths will be flashing red instead of the usual yellow. This indicates that it is impassable unless the player locates and destroys the Generator Boss that is creating the field. Therefore, it is imperative to find the right paths through the fortress to get to the Generator and blow it up. Once this is done, it is possible to safely pass through the red gates and move onto the rest of the area, and eventually, the area boss. Each time a generator is destroyed the player will earn a capsule that increases total HP.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="31">Capcom</developer>
        <publisher id="31">Capcom</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
        <genreid>79</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/sectionz.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/sectionz.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1207432387">
        <path>seikepsyj.zip</path>
        <name>Seiken Psychocalibur - Majuu no Mori Densetsu (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <cloneof>seikepsy.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="4125829425">
        <path>seikepsy.zip</path>
        <name>Seiken Psychocalibur - Majuu no Mori Densetsu (T-Eng)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="1763184861">
        <path>sexyinvaders.zip</path>
        <name>Sexy Invaders (Japan)</name>
        <desc>An adult version of the classic arcade game Space Invaders which upon beating levels you get to see various girls undress.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="12322">Super Pig</developer>
        <publisher id="2890">Hacker International</publisher>
        <genre>Adult</genre>
        <genreid>413</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/sexyinvaders.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/sexyinvaders.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1752153402">
        <path>silvij.zip</path>
        <name>Silviana - Ai Ippai no Little Angel (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <cloneof>silvi.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="32888458">
        <path>silvi.zip</path>
        <name>Silviana - Ai Ippai no Little Angel (T-Eng)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="819239068">
        <path>smashpingpong.zip</path>
        <name>Smash Ping Pong (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Smash Ping Pong simulates the game of ping-pong or table tennis in a remarkably different manner than prior simulations of any variety of tennis. Rather than putting the emphasis on precise control and placement of the paddle in order to return the ball, the emphasis is on timing and strategic control of the ball's speed and trajectory. The player sees no other on-screen representation of themselves beyond a hand holding a paddle. The hand and the paddle automatically move left and right to match the horizontal position of the ball. Players need only concern themselves with the timing of their paddle swing, and the style of swing to use. Players can choose between three different swings, along with the choice of forehand or backhand. 

The Famicom Disk System conversion was developed by Konami, and published directly by Nintendo as Smash Ping Pong. As a result,Konami's penguin mascot Pentarou was replaced by Diskun, the Famicom Disk System mascot, on the title screen, and Donkey Kong Jr. appears in the stands on the right side. The conversion offers several variations of play, including one or two player games, plays to 11 or 21 points, and five levels of difficulty. Additionally, Deuce win conditions do not end at 15 points, but can climb as high as 99 points.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Sports / Table tennis</genre>
        <genreid>2966</genreid>
        <players>2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/smashpingpong.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/smashpingpong.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="926898643">
        <path>solomonnokagi.zip</path>
        <name>Solomon no Kagi (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The main character, named Dana, is sent to retrieve "Solomon's Key" to restore the world to light from demons that were accidentally released. The object of the game is to advance through the 50 rooms of "Constellation Space" by acquiring a key to the door that leads to the next room before a timer runs out. The game incorporates elements of the platform shooter genre. Dana can run, jump, create or destroy orange blocks adjacent to him as well as create fireballs to destroy demons. The orange blocks can also be destroyed by hitting them with the character's head twice. Along the way Dana can acquire items to upgrade his firepower and extra lives as well as items that award bonus points and unlock hidden rooms. With certain items, Dana must make, then break blocks (sometimes in a certain manner) to make these appear.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="200">Tecmo</developer>
        <publisher id="200">Tecmo</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/solomonnokagi.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/solomonnokagi.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="517600189">
        <path>superboyallan.zip</path>
        <name>Super Boy Allan (Japan)</name>
        <desc>In the game, Allan Colada journeys from his home in the foothills into the mountains to retrieve a remedy for his sister Leela's fever.

Super Boy Allan is the second game in Sunsoft's "Intelligence Game" edutainment series for the Famicom Disk System, featuring two different game modes.

The first game mode, which is also the main game, the player has to avoid contact with enemies and push logs in order to solve math-based problems to get extra items. Solving math problems also increases your ability to move several logs at once, which is needed to make further progress.

The second, and much simpler game mode, has the player to finish a 39-steps marathon run by correctly answering simple math questions to accumulate as many points as possible.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="37">Sunsoft</developer>
        <publisher id="37">Sunsoft</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/superboyallan.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/superboyallan.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="174819441">
        <path>superlodrun.zip</path>
        <name>Super Lode Runner (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Douglas E. Smith's Lode Runner was introduced to Japan in 1983 on various popular Japanese home computer platforms, including the MSX, Sharp X1, and NEC PC family computers. Hudson Soft licensed the rights to bring the game to Nintendo's Famicom, and it was released in 1984 as one of the first 3rd party games ever made for the system and it was an incredible hit. Around the same time, Irem licensed the rights to produce an arcade version of Lode Runner which they also released in 1984, along with three other sequels through 1986. These arcade versions made a few tweaks to the original game play, and the final arcade game introduced a two player cooperative mode.

In 1987, Irem decided to package a number of select stages from all four of the arcade games into one title, and released it in disk format for the Famicom Disk System, entitled Super Lode Runner. Though the graphics were not quite as good as the arcade games, they were close, and Irem brought many of the game play changes to Famicom players, including the new two player mode. Irem released a sequel later on that same year. A different version of the game was released for the MSX with the same title.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="279">Irem</developer>
        <publisher id="279">Irem</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/superlodrun.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/superlodrun.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1122678538">
        <path>superlodrunii.zip</path>
        <name>Super Lode Runner II (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The second compilation of levels from Irem's Lode Runner Arcade series. Developed for the Famicom Disk System, it was never released outside of Japan.
Irem created four Arcade versions of the original Lode Runner, each with a unique set of levels as well as added features like a co-operative mode for two players. For the FDS home versions, Irem compiled several levels from each of these Arcade versions onto one disk. Super Lode Runner II has fewer single-player levels than its predecessor, but contains more co-op levels to make up for it.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="279">Irem</developer>
        <publisher id="279">Irem</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/superlodrunii.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/superlodrunii.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4218745260">
        <path>supermarbro.zip</path>
        <name>Super Mario Brothers (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Do you have what it takes to save the Mushroom Princess?

You'll have to think fast and move even faster to complete this quest! The Mushroom Princess is being held captive by the evil Koopa tribe of turtles. It's up to you to rescue her from the clutches of the Koopa King before time runs out. But it won't be easy. To get to the princess, you'll have to climb mountains, cross seas, avoid bottomless pits, fight off turtle soldiers and a host of black magic traps that only a Koopa King can devise. It's another non-stop adventure from the SUPER MARIO BROTHERS!</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/supermarbro.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/supermarbro.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2475501086">
        <path>supermarbroc.zip</path>
        <name>Super Mario Brothers (Japan) - Castellano v1.0</name>
        <desc>Do you have what it takes to save the Mushroom Princess?

You'll have to think fast and move even faster to complete this quest! The Mushroom Princess is being held captive by the evil Koopa tribe of turtles. It's up to you to rescue her from the clutches of the Koopa King before time runs out. But it won't be easy. To get to the princess, you'll have to climb mountains, cross seas, avoid bottomless pits, fight off turtle soldiers and a host of black magic traps that only a Koopa King can devise. It's another non-stop adventure from the SUPER MARIO BROTHERS!</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <cloneof>supermarbro.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/supermarbro.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/supermarbro.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3966841893">
        <path>supermarbro2.zip</path>
        <name>Super Mario Brothers 2 (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="4282089456">
        <path>tamafri.zip</path>
        <name>Tama &amp; Friends - 3 Choume Daibouken (Japan)</name>
        <releasedate>1989?0101T000000</releasedate>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
    </game>
    <game id="3645639465">
        <path>tennis.zip</path>
        <name>Tennis (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The game features single-player and two-player modes for singles and doubles matches, with either competitive or cooperative gameplay. A computerized opponent's artificial intelligence can be set to one of five difficulty levels. Mario referees the matches.</desc>
        <releasedate>19830101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="456">Intelligent Systems</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Sports / Tennis</genre>
        <genreid>2867</genreid>
        <players>1-16</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/tennis.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/tennis.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="808497521">
        <path>tobiddai.zip</path>
        <name>Tobidase Daisakusen (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Tobidase Daisakusen was developed by Square in 1987 and was published by DOG, a now-defunct label of Square. The North American release, which was the first Square game to reach American shores, was published by Acclaim Entertainment, Inc. for the NES under the name The 3-D Worldrunner.

The gameplay can best be described as an attempt to merge Super Mario Bros. game mechanics with Space Harrier's third person perspective. In the game, the player assumes the role of Jack, a wild "space cowboy" on a mission to save various planets overrun by serpent-like beasts. The game takes place in Solar System #517, which is being overrun by a race of aliens known as Serpentbeasts, who are led by the evil Grax. As WorldRunner, the player must battle through eight planets to destroy Grax. For its time, the game was technically advanced; the game's three dimensional scrolling effect is very similar to the linescroll effects used by Pole Position and many racing games of the day.

Part of the appeal and selling point of 3-D WorldRunner was its "3-D mode," and it was the first of three games by Square to feature such an option (the other two being JJ, the sequel to 3-D WorldRunner, and Rad Racer). When the 3-D mode is selected, the game uses computer image processing techniques to combine images from two slightly different viewpoints into a single image, known as anaglyph images. The game was packaged with cardboard "anaglyph glasses," which use red and cyan color filters to moderate the light reaching each eye to create the illusion of a three dimensional image.

Tobidase Daisakusen was designed by Hironobu Sakaguchi, Nobuo Uematsu, and Nasir Gebelli, all whom would later rise to fame as core members of the team behind the popular RPG Final Fantasy. The three also developed JJ - Tobidase Daisakusen Part II, the sequel to 3-D WorldRunner.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="8325">Square</developer>
        <publisher id="20237">Disk Original Group (DOG)</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/tobiddai.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/tobiddai.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2992166008">
        <path>topplezip.zip</path>
        <name>Topple Zip (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Topple Zip is a vertically scrolling shooter that is also labeled as a race game. The player pilots an air craft and flies in competition against several computer controlled craft. In addition to firing upon your opponents, you may ram into them (and they may ram into you) and dislodge a power-up from them which you can then shoot and collect. There are eight distinct scenes, each of which contain a number of warps which link to other scenes. How the scenes connect is random on each play through. The goal is to locate the key which is necessary to access to warp which leads to the eight and final scene, collect it from whichever scene it is hidden inside of, and access the eighth scene before any other competitor.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="10731">Bothtec</developer>
        <publisher id="10731">Bothtec</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
        <genreid>79</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/topplezip.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/topplezip.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4214114320">
        <path>trans.zip</path>
        <name>Transformers - The Headmasters (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Transformers: The Headmasters is a 1987 Family Computer Disk System game by Takara based on the popular cartoon series of the same name and released only in Japan. The game stars the Autobot Headmasters as the protagonists and playable characters. The game is infamous for its high level of difficulty and off-key background music.

You play as one of the Autobot Headmaster through four planets, fighting the Decepticons. Unlike it predecessor, Transformers: Convoy no Nazo, players cannot switch between robot and vehicle mode. Instead, each level contains an initial vehicle mode stage, followed by a robot mode stage. Players start out with only Chromedome. They can switch between Autobots at any time, but only if that Autobot has been collected. Players must rescue them throughout the game, as they will be flown in by helicopter in the vehicle mode stage, or found in one of the rooms of the robot mode stage. Since Headmasters was developed for the FDS, it contains a save game feature similar to those found in early The Legend of Zelda and Metroid games.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="79">Takara</developer>
        <publisher id="79">Takara</publisher>
        <genre>Shooter</genre>
        <genreid>2646</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/trans.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/trans.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2487819152">
        <path>twinbee.zip</path>
        <name>TwinBee (Japan)</name>
        <desc>TwinBee can be played by up to 2-players simultaneously. The player takes control of a cartoon-like anthropomorphic spacecraft, with Player 1 taking control of TwinBee, the titular ship, while Player 2 controls WinBee. The game controls consists of a joystick and two buttons: one for shooting enemies in the air and the other for dropping bombs to ground enemies (similarly to Xevious).

The player's primary power-ups are bells that can be uncovered by shooting at the floating clouds where they're hidden. If the player continues shooting the bell after it appears, it will change into one of four other colors: the regular yellow bells only grant bonus points, the white bell will upgrade the player's gun into a twin cannon, the blue bell increases the player's speed (for up to five speed levels), the green bell will allow the player to create image copies of its ship for additional firepower, and the red bell will provide the player's ship a barrier that allows it to sustain more damage. The green and red bells cannot be combined together. Other power-ups can also be retrieved from ground enemies such as an alternate bell that gives the player's ship a three-way gun, a star which eliminates all on-screen enemies.

As with other games of the same genre, getting shot by a single enemy bullet will cause the player to lose a life. However, if the bullet only strikes either side of the ship instead, the player's ship will only lose one of its arms. If the player's ship loses both arms, it will lose the ability to throw bombs and the player must wait for an ambulance to arrive. The player must navigate their ship to the ambulance to repair their arms. However, if the player's ship loses both arms for the second time, no ambulance will arrive.

If two players are playing at the same time, they can align their ships vertically or horizontally together to perform more powerful attacks</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26">Konami</developer>
        <publisher id="26">Konami</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
        <genreid>79</genreid>
        <players>2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/twinbee.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/twinbee.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="565478684">
        <path>ultra.zip</path>
        <name>Ultraman - Kaijuu Teikoku no Gyakushuu (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Ultraman: Kaiju Teikoku no Gyakushu, loosely translated as "Ultraman: Counterattack of the Monster Empire" is a side scrolling platformer developed for the Family Computer Disk System and published by Bandai at the start of 1987. This game is the first Famicom game dealing with Ultraman. Ultraman 2 was a sequel developed as a simulation game, and Ultraman Club: Chikyuu Dakkan Sakusen was developed as an RPG utilizing the "chibi" or super-deformed style of artwork for the characters.

The player controls Hayate, a member of the Science Special Search Party, which protects the earth from invasions of large hostile aliens. He must run across each stage, defeating enemies with his ray gun. He must also collect energy orbs to fill a meter on the screen. When it is full, he can transform himself into the powerful Ultraman. Energy balls can appear under a variety of circumstance, such as beating an enemy or shooting points in space. Just like in the show, you can only be Ultraman for 3 minutes, and you can chop or kick the boss monsters. When only one minute remains, Ultraman will gain access to two secret powers, the Specium Ray, and the Cutting Halo. Once the boss monster is defeated, the stage is cleared.

If all 11 stages are cleared and the player continues, the game will change the character to Dan Moroboshi who can transform into Ultra Seven. Although Ultra Seven's capabilities are the same as Ultraman's, the defensive power of the enemies will be higher. There are two versions of this game, one which was distributed on disk, and one which was distributed through disk writing stations (made available on March 26, 1987) and they feature slightly different background music tunes.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="580">Bandai Namco</developer>
        <publisher id="580">Bandai Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/ultra.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/ultra.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1403814286">
        <path>ultra2.zip</path>
        <name>Ultraman 2 - Shutsugeki Katoku Tai (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Ultraman 2: Shutsugeki Katoku Tai!! (Loosely translated as Ultraman 2: Sortie Department Group) is an action game developed by Bandai for the Famicom Disk System and published at the end of 1987. As the title implies, it revolves around the Ultraman series that was popular in Japan. However, rather than making Ultraman the focus of this game, it is the defense support team that goes into action whenever Japan is attacked by a giant monster which gets the majority of the game time.

The game takes place in modern Japan, with a bird's eye view presentation of much of Japan's metropolis. Players must send a team out to search for, and obtain, a cube which permits the defense team to damage monsters when they appear. Once the cube is found, monsters begin to appear and attack the buildings of Japan. The team must deploy vehicles to help aid in the destruction of these monsters until they have all been defeated. If a monster destroys a critical building, the game is instantly over.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="580">Bandai Namco</developer>
        <publisher id="580">Bandai Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/ultra2.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/ultra2.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1872160655">
        <path>ultraclu.zip</path>
        <name>Ultraman Club - Chikyuu Dakkan Sakusen (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Ultraman Club: Chikyuu Dakkan Sakusen ("Earth Protection Strategy" roughly) is a Bandai licensed game and the third Famicom Disk System game to be based on the Ultraman tokusatsu/kaiju TV show. The concept behind the "Ultraman Club" was to consolidate all the different variants of Ultraman from his many appearances in the different shows and have the player control a party of them.

Unlike the two prior games, which were more action-oriented, this game is a turn-based RPG.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="580">Bandai Namco</developer>
        <publisher id="580">Bandai Namco</publisher>
        <genre>Role playing games</genre>
        <genreid>8</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/ultraclu.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/ultraclu.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2358009033">
        <path>volleyball.zip</path>
        <name>Volleyball (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The game enables the player to choose the amount of people on their team, their country and their gender. The countries include the United States, China, Japan, South Korea, Brazil, Cuba, Russia (USR), and Tunisia. 

In the game the player will control their players by using the d-pad, and will use the b button to perform the game's various actions. The a button is not used in Volleyball. On the court there are two rows, 1 and 2. When the ball nears one of the rows, the team members in that row will then be able to be controlled by the player. If you are unable to hit the ball over the net, then the opposing team receives one point. After hitting the ball to the other side, the other team may or may not hit it over. If they don't your team receives one point.

To serve, the player must press the b button, wait for the ball to come back down to them and then press the b button again. When the opposing team serves, you will have to quickly hit it back over. Occasionally when you simply hit the ball, it'll go straight up in the air. If this happens, you'll have to press the b button once more in order to hit it over.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="768">Pax Softnica</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Sports</genre>
        <genreid>685</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/volleyball.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/volleyball.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3871888117">
        <path>vsexcitebike.zip</path>
        <name>Vs. Excitebike (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Vs. Excitebike is a motorcross racing simulation game developed by Nintendo as a sequel to Excitebike for the Famicom Disk System. It was also released in the arcades but the Famicom Disk System is arguably better with additional features.  It comes with some improved features, including a simultaneous two player mode that the original game lacked, and an improved track save system (the tracks were saved to the writable portion of the disk). The music is completely different; none of the songs from the original game are present in this version, and a background theme is played during gameplay. There is also a new bonus round that has you jumping over trucks.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Race, Driving</genre>
        <genreid>28</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/vsexcitebike.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/vsexcitebike.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="3838689880">
        <path>wakusatogai.zip</path>
        <name>Wakusei Aton Gaiden (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Wakusei Aton Gaiden ("Planet Aton Side-Story") is a vertical-scrolling shoot 'em up that was created by the Japanese National Tax Agency (Kokuzeichou) in order to teach children and older players about the issues surrounding Japan's bubble economy by way of a sci-fi themed parable. The story concerns the eponymous planet Aton and two young pilots who attempt to save it from some sort of economy-based crisis - one that just so happens to manifests itself as an alien invasion. The game can be played by one or two players, with player one assuming the role of the male pilot Kanta while the second player assumes the role of the female pilot Yuki.

The game was made accessible to players via a system not unlike the Disk Writer service, though presumably as a government-funded game it was made freely available. It is thought that copies were given away at some manner of a Japanese tax awareness convention or from an educational group that went to various schools across the country to lecture students. As with many Disk Writer exclusive games, it is extremely difficult for modern day Famicom collectors to find.</desc>
        <releasedate>19900101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="26829">Kokuzeichou</developer>
        <publisher id="26829">Kokuzeichou</publisher>
        <genre>Shooter</genre>
        <genreid>2646</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/wakusatogai.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/wakusatogai.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="1463132419">
        <path>wardnernomori.zip</path>
        <name>Wardner no Mori (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Wardner no Mori  (Lit. Forest of Warnder) is a platform style arcade game developed by Toaplan and released by Taito in 1987. In America, the arcade game was released under the title Pyros. The player controls a character by the name of Dover through various forest stages in an attempt to save his kidnapped girlfriend from the evil Wardner. The simple run and jump controls are supplemented with the ability to throw balls of fire. Gold coins can be collected throughout the game and exchanged for extra abilities in a shop at the end of each level.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="110">Toaplan</developer>
        <publisher id="55">Taito</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/wardnernomori.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/wardnernomori.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2955267370">
        <path>wintergames.zip</path>
        <name>Winter Games (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Winter Games is a sports game developed by Epyx based on sports featured in the Winter Olympic Games. A snow-and-ice themed follow-up to the highly successful Summer Games.

The game was presented as a virtual multi-sport carnival called the "Epyx Winter Games" (there was no official IOC licensing in place) with up to 2 players each choosing a country to represent, and then taking turns competing in various events to try for a medal.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="18580">Epyx</developer>
        <publisher id="2870">Pony Canyon</publisher>
        <genre>Sports</genre>
        <genreid>685</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/wintergames.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/wintergames.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4202208010">
        <path>wreckingcrew.zip</path>
        <name>Wrecking Crew (Japan)</name>
        <desc>The player controls Mario (or Luigi in two-player mode) and attempts to destroy all of a certain set of objects with a large hammer on each of 100 levels. Mario cannot jump because of the hammer's weight. The player can select any level to start on from the title screen. Each level takes place on a playfield divided into an invisible grid, each space of which can contain one object. Objects include destructible walls, pillars, and ladders, indestructible barrels and ladders, bombs that destroy all connected destructible objects, and various enemies that Mario must avoid. Doors may also exist, which can be opened to cause enemies to move harmlessly into the background. The game also introduced a new character, a construction foreman named Spike (believed to be an early version of Wario), who chases Mario and attempts to disrupt him by knocking down objects and causing him to fall to the bottom of the playfield. The player starts the game with five lives and loses a life whenever Mario comes in contact with an enemy or fireball. The game is over when all lives are lost. The game can also be aborted at any time, and must be aborted if Mario becomes trapped in a barrel.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Puzzle-Game</genre>
        <genreid>26</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/wreckingcrew.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/wreckingcrew.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="341982850">
        <path>youkaiyashikij.zip</path>
        <name>Youkai Yashiki (Japan)</name>
        <desc>In Youkai Yashiki, you control a boy armed with a flashlight who must explore five stages and locate five talisman before locating and gaining access to a stage boss. The flashlight serves as a weapon against the monsters which inhabit each stage. Your life meter takes the form of a set of batteries. As your life diminishes, the batteries drain and the power of your flashlight, that is the distance that the beams can travel, decreases.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="5008">Casio</developer>
        <publisher id="279">Irem</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>youkaiyashiki.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/youkaiyashiki.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/youkaiyashiki.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2041004403">
        <path>youkaiyashiki.zip</path>
        <name>Youkai Yashiki (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>In Youkai Yashiki, you control a boy armed with a flashlight who must explore five stages and locate five talisman before locating and gaining access to a stage boss. The flashlight serves as a weapon against the monsters which inhabit each stage. Your life meter takes the form of a set of batteries. As your life diminishes, the batteries drain and the power of your flashlight, that is the distance that the beams can travel, decreases.</desc>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="5008">Casio</developer>
        <publisher id="279">Irem</publisher>
        <genre>Platform</genre>
        <genreid>7</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/youkaiyashiki.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/youkaiyashiki.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="196102926">
        <path>yuumaze.zip</path>
        <name>Yuu Maze (Japan)</name>
        <desc>Yuu Maze ("Maze Play") is a single-screen maze game akin to Namco's classic Pac-Man and its many other imitators in that the goal of the game is to drive the futuristic vehicle around a maze collecting dots while avoiding (or temporarily eliminating) the enemies. Taito, one of the largest manufacturers of Arcade games at the time (not to mention the creators of Space Invaders), would produce similarly Arcade-reminiscent games for the system in order to tap into the portion of the market nostalgic for classic Arcade experiences.Yuu Maze adds a few innovations to the format: Each maze has a different structure, different enemies and different lay-outs for the pellets that are required to complete the level; the player can find power-ups which grant weapons, shields and speed-ups to their vehicle. The player's vehicle also has some degree of inertia: There's a slight delay when attempting to accelerate after stopping or performing a U-turn, but if the player keeps moving and changes direction only at 90 degree intervals, they can keep moving at their maximum speed. This is often necessary to keep ahead of the fast moving enemies.</desc>
        <releasedate>19880101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="11038">Daiei Seisakusho</developer>
        <publisher id="55">Taito</publisher>
        <genre>Action</genre>
        <genreid>10</genreid>
        <players>1-2</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/yuumaze.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/yuumaze.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4169212781">
        <path>zanac.zip</path>
        <name>Zanac (Japan)</name>
        <desc>ZANAC A.I. is a 2D shoot them up game. You are flying fighter model ZANAC, a ship built by 256 Riot Fleet as man's last hope against total annihilation. On board are special weapons to help you blast your way through twelve screens of enemy creatures and destroy the system's home base. Zanac is divided into 12 "areas", which look like planets. The various locations range from deserts to jungles and from oceans to industrial zones, featuring many different types of enemies.

Zanac's unique artificial intelligence program can intensify the action based upon your level of skill. The better you are, the more powerful "The System". Examples of the A.I. (but not limited to) in this game: the enemies are generally coming randomly with their behavior based on factors like the position your ship in the screen, the place you last died; the shoot speed of the enemies and bosses do also vary.

At the end of each area (level) you'll have to fight the area boss. Area bosses are mainly based around huge, screen-filling bunker bases consisting of gun turrets and a "core". You have limited time for fighting against the area boss - a time out could mean failure in entering the next stage, and with the time running, more and more enemies were attacking as penalty.
</desc>
        <rating>0.45</rating>
        <releasedate>19870101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="2870">Pony Canyon</developer>
        <publisher id="48">Compile</publisher>
        <genre>Shoot'em Up</genre>
        <genreid>79</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="3" parentid="0">NES</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/zanac.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/zanac.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="4109716554">
        <path>zeldanodenj.zip</path>
        <name>Zelda no Densetsu - The Hyrule Fantasy (Japan)</name>
        <desc>A small kingdom in the land of Hyrule, the setting of the game, is engulfed in chaos after an army led by Ganon, the Prince of Darkness, invaded it and stole the Triforce of Power, a part of a magical artifact bestowing great strength. In an attempt to prevent Ganon from acquiring the Triforce of Wisdom, another of the pieces, Princess Zelda splits it and hides the eight fragments in secret dungeons throughout the land. Before the princess is eventually kidnapped by Ganon, she commands her nursemaid Impa to find someone courageous enough to save the kingdom. While wandering the land, the old woman is surrounded by Ganon's henchmen, though a young boy named Link appears and rescues her.  After hearing Impa's plea, he resolves to save Zelda and sets out to reassemble the scattered fragments of the Triforce of Wisdom, to become powerful enough to defeat Ganon.

The Legend of Zelda incorporates elements of action, adventure, and role-playing games. The player controls Link from a flip-screen overhead perspective as he travels in the overworld, a large outdoor map with varied environments. Link begins the game armed only with a small shield, but a sword becomes available to Link after he ventures into a cave that is accessible from the game's first map screen. Throughout the game, various characters aid Link by giving or selling equipment and clues. These people can be found in caves scattered throughout the overworld; some are readily accessible, while others are hidden behind obstacles such as rocks, trees, and waterfalls

Nintendo originally released the game as the launch title for the Family Computer's new Disk System peripheral. The Legend of Zelda was joined by a re-release of Super Mario Bros., Tennis, Baseball, Golf, Soccer, and Mahjong in its introduction of the Disk System. It made full use of the Disk Card media's advantages over traditional ROM cartridges with a disk size of 128 kilobytes, which was expensive to produce on cartridge format. Due to the still-limited amount of space on the disk, however, it was only in katakana. Rather than passwords, it used rewritable disks to save the game. It used the extra sound channel provided by the Disk System for certain sound effects; most notable are the sounds of Link's sword when his health is full, the roars and growls of dungeon bosses, and enemy death sounds. The sound effects used the Famicom's PCM channel in the cartridge version. It also used the microphone built into the Famicom's controller that was not included in the NES. This led to confusion in the U.S. as the instruction manual reads that Pols Voice, a rabbit-like enemy in the game, "hates loud noise". Blowing or shouting into the Famicom's microphone kills these creatures. However, they cannot be killed through use of the recorder, and on the NES must be killed with weapons.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>13</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <cloneof>zeldanoden.zip</cloneof>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/zeldanoden.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/zeldanoden.mp4</video>
    </game>
    <game id="2025982475">
        <path>zeldanoden.zip</path>
        <name>Zelda no Densetsu - The Hyrule Fantasy (T-Eng)</name>
        <desc>A small kingdom in the land of Hyrule, the setting of the game, is engulfed in chaos after an army led by Ganon, the Prince of Darkness, invaded it and stole the Triforce of Power, a part of a magical artifact bestowing great strength. In an attempt to prevent Ganon from acquiring the Triforce of Wisdom, another of the pieces, Princess Zelda splits it and hides the eight fragments in secret dungeons throughout the land. Before the princess is eventually kidnapped by Ganon, she commands her nursemaid Impa to find someone courageous enough to save the kingdom. While wandering the land, the old woman is surrounded by Ganon's henchmen, though a young boy named Link appears and rescues her.  After hearing Impa's plea, he resolves to save Zelda and sets out to reassemble the scattered fragments of the Triforce of Wisdom, to become powerful enough to defeat Ganon.

The Legend of Zelda incorporates elements of action, adventure, and role-playing games. The player controls Link from a flip-screen overhead perspective as he travels in the overworld, a large outdoor map with varied environments. Link begins the game armed only with a small shield, but a sword becomes available to Link after he ventures into a cave that is accessible from the game's first map screen. Throughout the game, various characters aid Link by giving or selling equipment and clues. These people can be found in caves scattered throughout the overworld; some are readily accessible, while others are hidden behind obstacles such as rocks, trees, and waterfalls

Nintendo originally released the game as the launch title for the Family Computer's new Disk System peripheral. The Legend of Zelda was joined by a re-release of Super Mario Bros., Tennis, Baseball, Golf, Soccer, and Mahjong in its introduction of the Disk System. It made full use of the Disk Card media's advantages over traditional ROM cartridges with a disk size of 128 kilobytes, which was expensive to produce on cartridge format. Due to the still-limited amount of space on the disk, however, it was only in katakana. Rather than passwords, it used rewritable disks to save the game. It used the extra sound channel provided by the Disk System for certain sound effects; most notable are the sounds of Link's sword when his health is full, the roars and growls of dungeon bosses, and enemy death sounds. The sound effects used the Famicom's PCM channel in the cartridge version. It also used the microphone built into the Famicom's controller that was not included in the NES. This led to confusion in the U.S. as the instruction manual reads that Pols Voice, a rabbit-like enemy in the game, "hates loud noise". Blowing or shouting into the Famicom's microphone kills these creatures. However, they cannot be killed through use of the recorder, and on the NES must be killed with weapons.</desc>
        <releasedate>19860101T000000</releasedate>
        <developer id="286">Nintendo</developer>
        <publisher id="286">Nintendo</publisher>
        <genre>Adventure</genre>
        <genreid>13</genreid>
        <players>1</players>
        <system id="106" parentid="3">Family Computer Disk System</system>
        <image type="mixrbv2">media/mixrbv2/zeldanoden.png</image>
        <video type="video">media/video/zeldanoden.mp4</video>
    </game>
</gameList>
